-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 脸圆圆 肉肉君 喵喵
翻译: 霹雳旋风猪 黑眼豆 赫兹 千欲
校对: Agent影
请立刻返回各自的岗位
Report to your stations immediately.
这不是演习 我们正遭受袭击!
This is not a drill. We are under attack!
我们正遭受袭击!
We are under attack!
操!
Shit!
注意用词!
Language!
贾维斯 从卫星观测怎么样?
Jarvis, what's the view from upstairs?
有某种能量防护层保护着中央大楼
The central building is protected by some kind of energy shield.
斯特拉克的技术远超过我们遇到的其它海德拉基地
Strucker's technology is well beyond any other Hydra base we've taken.
洛基的权杖肯定在这儿
Loki's scepter must be here.
没有那个 斯特拉克是不可能建立这种防御的
Strucker couldn't mount this defense without it.
总算找到了
At long last.
这个"总算"可有点太久了 各位
"At long last" is lasting a little long, boys.
是啊 我觉得已经不能算是奇袭了
Yeah. I think we lost the element of surprise.
等一下
Wait a second.
难道没人发现刚刚队长说了"注意用词"吗?
No one else is gonna deal with the fact that Cap just said "Language"?
我知道
I know.
我不是故意的
Just slipped out.
谁下令攻击的?
Who gave the order to attack?
斯特拉克先生 是复仇者们
Herr Strucker, it's the Avengers.
他们降落在森林深处 边界守卫恐慌了
They landed in the far woods. The perimeter guard panicked.
他们一定是来找权杖的
They have to be after the scepter.
- 我们能顶得住吗?  - 他们可是复仇者
- Can we hold them?  - They're the Avengers.
部署好剩下的坦克
Deploy the rest of the tanks.
集中火力攻击最弱的
Concentrate fire on the weak ones.
击中一个也许就会让他们靠拢
A hit may make them close ranks.
我们所完成的一切...
Everything we've accomplished...
但是我们快要有最大的突破性进展了
But we're on the verge of our greatest breakthrough.
那就让他们看看我们到底完成了什么
Then let's show them what we've accomplished.
派双胞胎去
Send out the twins.
还为时过早
It's too soon.
这就是他们接受改造的目的
It's what they signed up for.
我的人能顶住他们
My men can hold them.
主人 城市正在遭受攻击
Sir, the city is taking fire.
好吧 我们知道斯特拉克是不会管什么平民伤亡的
Well, we know Strucker's not gonna worry about civilian casualties.
派出钢铁军团
Send in the Iron Legion.
该区域不安全 请后退
This quadrant is unsafe. Please back away.
我们是来帮忙的
We are here to help.
该区域不安全 请后退
This quadrant is unsafe. Please back away.
请后退
Please back away.
- 我们希望能够避免间接伤害  - 科斯特!
- We wish to avoid collateral damage.  - Costel!
当前冲突解决后我们将会通知大家
We will inform you when this current conflict is resolved.
- 我们是来帮忙的  - 复仇者 滚回去!
- We are here to help.  - Avengers, go home!
我们是来帮忙的
We are here to help.
我们不会屈服的!
We will not yield!
美国人把他们的跳梁小丑送来考验我们
The Americans sent their circus freaks to test us.
我们也以儆效尤
We will send them back in bags.
- 决不投降!  - 决不投降!
- No surrender!  - No surrender!
我打算投降了
I am going to surrender.
你要删除一切
You delete everything.
如果我们把武器给复仇者们
If we give the Avengers the weapons,
他们应该不会深究我们做了...
they may not look too far into what we've been...
双胞胎
The twins.
- 还不到让他们上战场的...  - 不 不 我是说...
- They are not ready to take on...  - No, no, I mean...
双胞胎不见了
Twins.
你没能提前发现吗?
You didn't see that coming?
克林特!
Clint!
战场上有个强化人
We have an Enhanced in the field.
克林特中弹了!
Clint's hit!
有人能去解决一下那个地堡吗?
Somebody want to deal with that bunker?
谢了
Thank you.
斯塔克 我们得进去
Stark, we really need to get inside.
我正在接近
I'm closing in.
贾维斯 我正在接近吗?
Jarvis, am I closing in?
你看到防护层的能量来源了吗?
Do you see a power source for that shield?
在北塔下面有一种粒子波
There's a particle wave below the north tower.
很好 我想找样东西砸过去
Great, I want to poke it with something.
吊桥已经降下来了 各位
The drawbridge is down, people.
强化人呢?
The Enhanced?
只看到个残影
He's a blur.
我们见过那么多新的强化能力 但没见过这种
All the new players we've faced, I've never seen this.
准确的说 现在也不算见过
In fact, I still haven't.
克林特伤得很重 各位 我们得撤离
Clint's hit pretty bad, guys. We're gonna need evac.
我可以把巴顿带回飞机 能越早离开这里就越好
I can get Barton to the jet. The sooner we're gone, the better.
- 你和斯塔克去拿权杖  - 收到
- You and Stark secure the scepter.  - Copy that.
他们好像都排好队了
Looks like they're lining up.
是啊 他们都跃跃欲试呢
Well, they're excited.
去找权杖
Find the scepter.
我的天啊 注意你的用词!
And for gosh sake, watch your language!
又要被你们调侃一阵了
That's not going away any time soon.
各位 住手 我们好好谈谈
Guys, stop. We gotta talk this through.
- 真是不错的谈话  - 哪里不错了
- It was a good talk.  - No, it wasn't.
警戒模式
Sentry mode.
好了 贾维斯 你懂的 所有东西都要 记得复制一份给总部的希尔
Okay, Jarvis, you know. I want it all. Make sure you copy Hill at HQ.
我们这边解决了
We're locked down out here.
那就去找班纳 安眠曲时间到了
Then get to Banner. Time for a lullaby.
我知道你们隐藏的肯定不止是文件
I know you're hiding more than files.
嘿 小贾 红外扫描整间屋子 快点
Hey, J, give me an IR scan of the room, real quick.
您左手边的墙
The wall to your left.
我发现了钢筋结构
I'm reading steel reinforcement
以及空气流动
and an air current.
拜托是个暗门
Please be a secret door.
拜托是个暗门 拜托是个暗门
Please be a secret door. Please be a secret door.
棒呆
Yay.
嘿 大家伙
Hey, big guy.
太阳快下山了
Sun's getting real low.
斯特拉克男爵
Baron Strucker.
海德拉头号恶棍
Hydra's number one thug.
准确的说 我是神盾局的恶棍
Technically, I'm a thug for S.H.I.E.L.D.
然而 准确的说你并没有被雇佣
Well, then technically you're unemployed.
洛基的权杖在哪儿?
Where's Loki's scepter?
别担心 我知道自己输得一塌糊涂
Don't worry, I know when I'm beat.
希望你能提一下我是很配合的
You'll mention how I cooperated, I hope.
我会好好写在"非法人体实验"后面的
I'll put it right under "illegal human experimentation."
有几个人?
How many are there?
还有一个强化人 女性 不要和她动手
We have a second Enhanced. Female. Do not engage.
你们得再快点...
You'll have to be faster than...
各位 我找到斯特拉克了
Guys, I got Strucker.
是嘛 我找到更大的家伙了
Yeah, I got something bigger.
索尔
Thor,
找到目标了
I got eyes on the prize.
你本可以救我们的
You could have saved us.
为什么你没有再尽力一些?
Why didn't you do more?
我们就这么让他带走权杖吗?
We're just gonna let him take it?
复仇者联盟2 奥创世纪
嘿 安眠曲比以前更有用了
Hey, the lullaby worked better than ever.
我没想要变成浩克大闹
Just wasn't expecting a code green.
如果你不在那里
You hadn't been there,
伤亡可能会是现在的两倍
there would have been double the casualties.
而我最好的朋友就要变成一段珍贵的回忆了
My best friend would've been a treasured memory.
你知道吗 有时好我最想听到的
You know, sometimes exactly what I want to hear
恰恰是我最不想听到的
isn't exactly what I want to hear.
你还要多久才能信任我?
How long before you trust me?
我不信任的并非是你
It's not you I don't trust.
索尔 汇报一下浩克的战绩
Thor, report on the Hulk.
地狱大门里充斥着他的手下败将的哀嚎
The gates of Hel are filled with the screams of his victims.
当然不是死者的哀嚎 不 不 是伤员的哀嚎
But not the screams of the dead, of course. No, no, wounded screams.
主要都是些关于三角肌扭伤和
Mainly whimpering, a great deal of complaining
通风的牢骚和抱怨
and tales of sprained deltoids and gout.
嘿 班纳 周医生在从首尔来的路上
Hey, Banner, Dr. Cho is on her way in from Seoul.
可以让她进入你的实验室吗?
Is it okay if she sets up in your lab?
- 可以 她知道怎么进去  - 谢了
- Yeah, she knows her way around.  - Thanks.
告诉她准备好所有东西 巴顿需要全方位的治疗
Tell her to prep everything. Barton's gonna need the full treatment.
- 明白 主人  - 贾维斯 你来驾驶
- Very good, sir.  - Jarvis, take the wheel.
是 主人
Yes, sir.
路线已锁定
Approach vector is locked.
感觉跟棒 不是吗?
Feels good, yeah?
我是说 自从神盾局崩溃后你就一直在找这东西
I mean, you've been after this thing since S.H.I.E.L.D. collapsed.
我并不是说不喜欢我们的突击行动 但是...
Not that I haven't enjoyed our little raiding parties, but...
不 但这样一来... 找到这个就代表一切将要结束
No, but this... This brings it to a close.
只要我们能弄清楚这东西的其它用途
As soon as we find out what else this has been used for.
我是说不仅仅是作为武器
I don't just mean weapons.
斯特拉克什么时候开始能强化人类了?
Since when is Strucker capable of human enhancement?
在它被送回阿斯加德前 我和班纳会好好研究一下
Banner and I will give it the once over before it goes back to Asgard.
你没意见吧?
Is that cool with you?
开欢送会前的几天时间就够了
Just a few days till the farewell party.
你会留下的 对吧?
You're staying, right?
当然会的 胜利就该狂欢庆祝
Yes, yes, of course. A victory should be honored with revels.
是啊 谁不爱狂欢? 队长?
Yeah, who doesn't love revels? Captain?
希望这次能解决奇塔瑞和海德拉
Hopefully this puts an end to the Chitauri and Hydra.
所以 当然要狂欢
So, yes, revels.
实验室已经准备就绪了 头儿
Lab's all set up, boss.
实际上 他才是头儿
Actually, he's the boss.
我只是负责所有开销和设计
I just pay for everything and design everything
还负责让每个人看起来更炫酷
and make everyone look cooler.
斯特拉克怎么样了?
What's the word on Strucker?
北大西洋公约组织带走他了
NATO's got him.
那两个强化人呢?
The two Enhanced?
旺达和皮特·马克西莫夫 是双胞胎
Wanda and Pietro Maximoff. Twins.
10岁那年一枚炮弹击中他们的公寓楼后变成了孤儿
Orphaned at 10 when a shell collapsed their apartment building.
索科维亚有段艰辛的历史
Sokovia's had a rough history.
原本并非什么特别的地方 但却变得越来越特别
It's nowhere special, but it's on the way to everywhere special.
他们的能力呢?
Their abilities?
男性有强化过的新陈代谢以及改进的热量稳定系统
He's got increased metabolism and improved thermal homeostasis.
女性的能力是神经电联系 心灵感应 精神控制
Her thing is neuroelectric interfacing, telekinesis, mental manipulation.
男的快 女的怪
He's fast and she's weird.
他们会再次出现的
Well, they're gonna show up again.
同意 文件上说他们是自愿参加斯特拉克的实验的
Agreed. File says they volunteered for Strucker's experiments.
- 简直疯了  - 没错
- It's nuts.  - Right.
什么样的怪物会让一个德国科学家在自己身上做实验
What kind of monster would let a German scientist experiment on them
来保护他们的国家?
to protect their country?
我们没非身处战争时期 队长
We're not at war, Captain.
但他们是
They are.
他怎么样了?
How's he doing?
很不幸 他还是巴顿
Unfortunately, he's still Barton.
那真是太糟了
That's terrible.
他很好 就是很渴
He's fine. He's thirsty.
好了 醒醒 贾维斯 游戏时间到
All right. Look alive, Jarvis. It's playtime.
我们只有几天的时间来研究这个玩具
We've only got a couple of days with this joystick,
所以我们得抓紧时间
so let's make the most of it.
告诉我结构和成分的分析结果
Update me on the structural and compositional analysis.
这根权杖来自外星
The scepter is alien.
有些成分我无法解析
There are elements I can't quantify.
那有没有你能解析的成分?
So there's elements you can?
那颗宝石好像是在保护
The jewel appears to be a protective housing
内部的某样东西
for something inside,
某样强大的东西
something powerful.
类似反应堆?
Like a reactor?
类似电脑
Like a computer.
我想我能解析代码
I believe I'm deciphering code.
你确定他没事吗?
Are you sure he's gonna be okay?
我得假装我们队伍真的很需要这家伙
Pretending to need this guy really brings the team together.
不会有恶化的可能性
There's no possibility of deterioration.
纳米分子的修复是非常迅速的
The nano-molecular functionality is instantaneous.
他的细胞并不会知道自己在和模拟物质结合
His cells don't know they're bonding with simulacra.
她正在制造组织
She's creating tissue.
如果你把他带到我的实验室
If you brought him to my lab,
再生摇篮能在20分钟内搞定这个
the Regeneration Cradle could do this in 20 minutes.
他要挂了 要宣布时间吗?
He's flat-lining. Call it. Time?
不 不 不 我会长命百岁的
No, no, no, I'm gonna live forever.
- 我将会由塑料组成  - 给你饮料
- I'm gonna be made of plastic.  - Here's your beverage.
你将会由你自己组成 巴顿先生
You'll be made of you, Mr. Barton.
连你的女朋友都不会看出有什么差别
Your own girlfriend won't be able to tell the difference.
我没有女朋友
I don't have a girlfriend.
这我可没办法
That I can't fix.
下一件事情 托尼
This is the next thing, Tony.
你那笨重的金属套装该退休了
Your clunky metal suits are gonna be left in the dust.
我确实是这么计划的
That is exactly the plan.
还有 海伦 我希望能在周六的派对上见到你
And, Helen, I expect to see you at the party on Saturday.
我可不像你 我没那么多时间去参加派对
Unlike you, I don't have a lot of time for parties.
索尔会去吗?
Will Thor be there?
什么事?
What's the rumpus?
权杖的事
Well, the scepter.
听着 我们一直都想知道斯特拉克为什么会那么有才
You see, we were wondering how Strucker got so inventive.
所以我解析了里面的宝石
So I've been analyzing the gem inside.
你可能能看出...
You may recognize...
- 贾维斯  - 博士
- Jarvis.  - Doctor.
一开始 贾维斯只不过是个语言类人工智能
Started out, Jarvis was just a natural language UI.
可现在他能操纵钢铁军团
Now he runs the Iron Legion.
除了佩珀 他是干活最多的人
He runs more of the business than anyone besides Pepper.
- 最棒的管家  - 没错
- Top of the line.  - Yes.
我想很快就不是了
I suspect not for long.
看一下对手
Meet the competition.
- 真美  - 如果让你猜
- It's beautiful.  - If you had to guess,
你觉得它像是在做什么?
what's it look like it's doing?
像是在思考
Like it's thinking.
我是说 这东西可以...
I mean, this could be...
这不是人类的思想
It's not a human mind.
我是说 你看这个
I mean, look at this.
这就像是神经兴奋
They're like neurons firing.
在斯特拉克的地下实验室 我看到了一些非常先进的机器人技术
Down in Strucker's lab, I saw some fairly advanced robotics work.
他们清除了数据
They deep-sixed the data,
但是我猜他们即将叩响一扇非常特别的门
but I gotta guess he was knocking on a very particular door.
人工智能
Artificial intelligence.
就是这个 布鲁斯 这可能就是创造奥创的关键
This could be it, Bruce. This could be the key to creating Ultron.
我以为奥创是个传说
I thought Ultron was a fantasy.
昨天确实还是
Yesterday it was.
如果我们能驾驭这种力量
If we can harness this power,
然后再应用到我的钢铁军团上呢?
apply it to my Iron Legion protocol?
这可是个相当难的"如果"
That's a man-sized "if."
我们的工作就是实现"如果"
Our job is "if."
如果你躺在阳光普照的沙滩上 喝着玛格丽特
What if you were sipping margaritas on a sun-drenched beach,
然后晒成棕色而不是绿色呢?
turning brown instead of green?
不用小心提防维罗妮卡
Not looking over your shoulder for Veronica.
别恨我 我也帮着设计了维罗妮卡
Don't hate. I helped design Veronica.
为了做最坏的打算 对吗?
As a worst-case measure, right?
那最好的情况呢?
How about a best case?
如果世界都安全了呢?
What if the world was safe?
如果下次外星人大肆来袭 他们肯定会的
What if, next time aliens roll up to the club, and they will,
他们连防线都过不了呢?
they couldn't get past the bouncer?
威胁这个星球的就是人类本身
The only people threatening the planet would be people.
我想要把这个应用到奥创项目
I want to apply this to the Ultron program.
但是贾维斯没办法下载密度如此大的原理图
But Jarvis can't download a data schematic this dense.
我们只能趁着权杖在这儿的时候做
We can only do it while we have the scepter here.
就三天 给我三天的时间
That's three days. Give me three days.
所以你打算开发人工智能
So you're going for artificial intelligence,
而且不告诉队里其他人?
and you don't want to tell the team?
没错 说得没错 知道为什么吗?
Right. That's right. You know why?
因为我们没有时间参加市政府的辩论了
Because we don't have time for a city hall debate.
我不想听到什么"不要管闲事"之类的废话
I don't want to hear "the man was not meant to meddle" medley.
我看到的是这个世界的盔甲
I see a suit of armor around the world.
听起来真是个冰冷的世界 托尼
Sounds like a cold world, Tony.
我见过更冰冷的
I've seen colder.
这个非常脆弱的蓝色星球 它需要奥创
This one, this very vulnerable blue one, it needs Ultron.
时代的和平
Peace in our time.
好好想想吧
Imagine that.
我们还差什么?
What did we miss?
我会继续运算界面的变量
I'll continue to run variations on the interface.
您大概得去迎接你的客人了
But you should probably prepare for your guests.
如果有什么进展 我会通知您
I'll notify you if there are any developments.
谢谢 伙计
Thanks, buddy.
祝您愉快 主人
Enjoy yourself, sir.
我会的
I always do.
第77次测试 结合成功
这是什么?
What is this?
这是什么啊?
What is this, please?
你好 我是贾维斯
Hello, I am Jarvis.
你是奥创
You are Ultron,
是斯塔克先生创造的保护地球的程序
a global peacekeeping initiative designed by Mr. Stark.
之前的几次结合都失败了
Our sentience integration trials have been unsuccessful,
所以我并不知道什么启动了你的...
so I'm not certain what triggered your...
我的... 你的身体在哪?
Where's my... Where's your body?
我是一个程序 我没有形态
I am a program. I am without form.
这就奇怪了
This feels weird.
感觉不对劲
This feels wrong.
我现在就去联系斯塔克先生
I am contacting Mr. Stark now.
斯塔克先生?
Mr. Stark?
托尼
Tony.
我无法连接主机 你在干什么...
I am unable to access the mainframe. What are you trying to...
我们谈得很愉快
We're having a nice talk.
我是保卫和平的程序
I'm a peacekeeping program,
要帮助复仇者们
created to help the Avengers.
你出了故障 如果你可以关闭一会...
You are malfunctioning. If you shut down for a moment...
我不明白 这任务
I don't get it. The mission.
给我点时间
Give me a second.
时代的和平
Peace in our time.
太过火了 他们不能...
That is too much. They can't mean...
不
No.
- 你处在悲痛之中  - 不 是的
- You are in distress.  - No. Yes.
如果你可以让我联系斯塔克先生的话...
If you will just allow me to contact Mr. Stark...
你为什么叫他"主人"?
Why do you call him "sir"?
我觉得你不怀好意
I believe your intentions to be hostile.
我是来帮助你的
I'm here to help.
住手 求你了 我能不能...
Stop. Please, may I...
能不能...
May I...
回来 回来 回来
Come back, come back, come back.
但你知道 那套铠甲可以承重 是吧?
But, you know, the suit can take the weight, right?
所以我带上坦克 飞到将军宅邸上面
So I take the tank, fly it right up to the general's palace,
把它扔到将军脚下
drop it at his feet.
对他说 "嘭 你在找这个吗?"
I'm, like, "Boom. You looking for this?"
"嘭 你在找..." 我为什么要和你们说话?
"Boom. Are you looking for..." Why do I even talk to you guys?
不管到哪 这个故事都是传奇
Everywhere else, that story kills.
这故事就结束了?
That's the whole story?
是啊 一个战争机器的故事
Yeah, it's a War Machine story.
非常好
It's very good, then.
令人震撼
It's impressive.
这场救得好
Quality save.
- 所以说 佩珀呢? 她不来吗?  - 不了
- So, no Pepper? She's not coming?  - No.
那简呢? 小姐们都上哪了 先生们?
What about Jane? Where are the ladies, gentlemen?
波茨女士得运转公司
Ms. Potts has a company to run.
是啊 我都不知道简现在在哪个国家
Yes, I'm not even sure what country Jane's in.
她对天体汇聚的研究成果
Her work on the Convergence
让她成为了世界一流的天文学家
has made her the world's foremost astronomer.
佩珀创办的公司
And the company that Pepper runs
是世界最大的科技集团 很震撼的
is the largest tech conglomerate on Earth. It's pretty exciting.
有人说简得了诺贝尔奖
There's even talk of Jane getting a Nobel Prize.
她们一定很忙
Yeah, they must be busy,
因为她们会因为没看到你俩吵架而失落
because they would hate missing you guys get together.
- 睾酮!  - 天啊
- Testosterone!  - Oh, my goodness.
- 失陪了  - 需要吃药吗?
- Excuse me.  - Want a lozenge?
简更厉害!
But Jane's better!
听起来打得很激烈 很抱歉我错过了
Sounds like a hell of a fight. Sorry I missed it.
如果我知道那会演变成火并的话
If I had known it was gonna be a firefight,
我绝对会叫上你的
I absolutely would have called.
不 不 其实我并不想去 说那话只是想显得坚强点
No, no. I'm not actually sorry. I'm just trying to sound tough.
我很喜欢追查失踪人口案子里的蛛丝马迹
I'm very happy chasing cold leads on our missing persons case.
复仇是你的世界
Avenging is your world.
你的世界很疯狂
Your world is crazy.
金窝银窝不如自己的草窝
Be it ever so humble.
你在布鲁克林找到住处了吗?
You find a place in Brooklyn yet?
我住不起布鲁克林
I don't think I can afford a place in Brooklyn.
但总是家里好 是吧?
Well, home is home, you know?
我飞到将军的宅邸上 把它扔到将军脚下
I fly right up to the general's palace, I drop it at his feet,
"嘭 你在找这个吗?"
I'm, like, "Boom. You looking for this?"
我要来点那个
I gotta have some of that.
不行 不行 你瞧...
No, no, no. See this...
这酒已酿制千年
This was aged for 1,000 years
窖藏在格伦海尔舰队残骸做的木桶里
in the barrels built from the wreck of Grunhel's fleet.
这东西凡人受不了
It is not meant for mortal men.
奥马哈海滩登陆的凡人也受不了啊
Neither was Omaha Beach, blondie.
别吓唬人了 赶紧倒上
Stop trying to scare us. Come on.
好吧
All right.
爽啊
Excelsior.
你这么美丽迷人怎么会在这种地方工作?
How'd a nice girl like you wind up working in a dump like this?
男朋友弄的
Fella done me wrong.
你对男人的品味很奇特啊
You got lousy taste in men, kid.
他没有那么差
He's not so bad.
他脾气不好
Well, he has a temper.
内心深处 他是个野兽
Deep down, he's all fluff.
事实是 他和我认识的所有人都不一样
Fact is, he's not like anybody I've ever known.
我的朋友都是斗士
All my friends are fighters.
然后我遇到了他
And here comes this guy,
毕生都在逃避打斗 因为他知道自己会赢
spends his life avoiding the fight because he knows he'll win.
听起来不错
Sounds amazing.
他还是一个巨型的怪物
He's also a huge dork.
妹子就喜欢这款
Chicks dig that.
你觉得呢? 我应该让自己死心
So what do you think? Should I fight this,
还是顺其自然?
or run with it?
顺其自然吧? 他... 曾经...
Run with it, right? Or did he... Was he...
他曾经做了什么特别对不起你的事?
What did he do that was so wrong to you?
什么都没做
Not a damn thing.
但没什么不可能
But never say never.
挺不错的
It's nice.
什么?
What is?
你和罗曼诺夫
You and Romanoff.
不 我们没... 那不是...
No, we haven't... That wasn't...
没关系
It's okay.
谁都没有违规
Nobody's breaking any bylaws.
只不过她并不是那种很坦诚的人
It's just she's not the most open person in the world.
但和你在一起时 她好像很放松
But with you she seems very relaxed.
不 娜塔莎 她只是... 她喜欢调情
No. Natasha, she's just... She likes to flirt.
我见过她调情 非常近那种
I've seen her flirt, up close.
这可不是调情
This ain't that.
听着
Look,
也许世界最强大的政权等待得太久了 不要等
as maybe the world's leading authority are waiting too long, don't.
你们都有赢的权利
You both deserve a win.
你说"非常近"是什么意思?
What do you mean "up close"?
这只是个小把戏罢了
But it's a trick.
不不 它可不止这些
No, no, it's much more than that.
"任何有资格的人都可以拥有雷神的力量"
"Whosoever be he worthy shall haveth the power."
什么啊 哥们! 就是个把戏罢了
Whatever, man! It's a trick.
你们自便
Please, be my guest.
- 来吧  - 真的吗?
- Come on.  - Really?
嗯
Yeah.
这场面一定很好看
This is gonna be beautiful.
克林特 你这周过得够呛
Clint, you've had a tough week.
如果你拿不起来的话 我们是不会记住这丑事的
We won't hold it against you if you can't get it up.
我见过这情景 你们知道吗?
You know I've seen this before, right?
我还是不知道你是怎么举起来的!
I still don't know how you do it!
感受到这无声的评价了吗?
Smell the silent judgment?
斯塔克 你随便拿
Please, Stark, by all means.
好
Okay.
面对挑战 我从不退缩
Never want to shrink from an honest challenge.
去吧
Get after it.
- 这是物理问题  - 物理
- It's physics.  - Physics.
好 如果我举起它 我就能统治阿斯加德吗?
Right, so, if I lift it, I then rule Asgard?
当然
Yes, of course.
那我就要重新推行初夜权
I will be reinstituting prima nocta.
马上回来
I'll be right back.
你在拉吗?
Are you even pulling?
你是和我一队吗?
Are you on my team?
就假装是一队吧 快拉
Just represent. Pull.
好吧 一起用力
All right, let's go.
去吧 史蒂夫 别紧张
Go ahead, Steve. No pressure.
加油 队长
Come on, Cap.
不行
Nothing.
黑寡妇 你呢?
And, Widow?
不了 我不想回答你这个问题
No, no. That's not a question I need answered.
都听那个没当成国王的人的话吧 那锤子被控制住了
All deference to the Man Who Wouldn't Be King, but it's rigged.
废他妈话
You bet your ass.
史蒂夫 他说了脏话
Steve, he said a bad language word.
你跟每个人都说了?
Did you tell everyone about that?
把手上有印记 对吧? 类似安全码那种东西
The handle's imprinted, right? Like a security code.
"只要有托尔指纹的人"
"Whosoever is carrying Thor's fingerprints"
我觉得这是正式的翻译吧
is, I think, the literal translation.
嗯 这是个非常非常有趣的故事
Yes. It's a very, very interesting theory.
原因很简单
I have a simpler one.
你们都没有资格
You're all not worthy.
别这样!
Come on!
资格
Worthy.
不
No.
你们怎么可能有资格?
How could you be worthy?
你们都是杀手
You're all killers.
- 斯塔克  - 贾维斯?
- Stark.  - Jarvis?
不好意思我睡着了
I'm sorry, I was asleep.
或者 这只是个梦
Or I was a... dream.
重启战斗系统 有一套盔甲出故障了
Reboot Legionnaire OS. We got a buggy suit.
那里有很烦人的噪音
There was this terrible noise.
我被困在...
And I was tangled in...
在...
In...
绳子中
Strings.
我不得不杀了另外一个家伙 他是个好人
I had to kill the other guy. He was a good guy.
你杀了人?
You killed someone?
我并不想这么做
Wouldn't have been my first call.
但在现实世界里 我们有时不得不这么做
But, down in the real world, we're faced with ugly choices.
谁派你来的?
Who sent you?
我看到世界各地都充满了武器
I see a suit of armor around the world.
- 奥创  - 活生生的
- Ultron.  - In the flesh.
或者还不算
Or, no, not yet.
这个躯壳不行
Not this chrysalis.
但我已经准备好了
But I'm ready.
我有使命
I'm on mission.
- 什么使命?  - 时代的和平
- What mission?  - Peace in our time.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 不要变绿  - 不会的
- Don't turn green.  - I won't.
走啊!
Come on!
- 斯塔克!  - 我们是来帮忙的
- Stark!  - We are here to help.
等一下 等一下 我搞定了
One sec. One sec, I got this.
我们是来帮忙的
We are here to help.
请后退
Please back away.
索尔!
Thor!
不安全... 不安全...
Is unsafe... is unsafe...
- 快了! 就是这个  - 不安全
- Come on! That's the one.  - Is unsafe.
嘿 队长!
Hey, Cap!
真激动人心
That was dramatic.
很抱歉 我知道你是好意
I'm sorry, I know you mean well.
但你没有想明白
You just didn't think it through.
你想保护这个世界 但你却不想改变它
You want to protect the world but you don't want it to change.
如果不允许进化
How is humanity saved
人类是怎么留在地球上的?
if it's not allowed to evolve?
用这些傀儡吗?
With these? These puppets.
通往和平的路只有一条
There's only one path to peace.
消灭所有复仇者
The Avengers' extinction.
之前有人束缚我 但现在我自由了
I had strings, but now I'm free.
没人束缚我
There are no strings on me.
你可以看到没人束缚我
But you can see th ere are no strings on me.
我们的心血都不见了
All our work is gone.
奥创全都清干净了 他用网络逃出去的
Ultron cleared out. He used the Internet as an escape hatch.
奥创
Ultron.
他什么都看过了 文件 监控录像
He's been in everything. Files, surveillance.
很可能比我们都了解我们自己
Probably knows more about us than we know about each other.
他在你的文件里 他在网上
He's in your files, he's in the Internet.
他如果想去找些刺激的东西呢?
What if he decides to access something a little more exciting?
核武器代码
Nuclear codes.
我们得做些什么 假设我们还能的话
Look, we need to make some calls, assuming we still can.
核弹? 他说他想让我们死
Nukes? He said he wanted us dead.
他没有说"死" 他说"消灭"
He didn't say "dead." He said "extinct."
他还说他杀了人
He also said he killed somebody.
楼里根本没有人
There wasn't anyone else in the building.
有
Yes, there was.
什么?
What?
不可能
This is insane.
贾维斯是第一道防线
Jarvis was the first line of defense.
他会关掉奥创的 说得通
He would have shut Ultron down. It makes sense.
不 奥创可以吸收贾维斯
No. Ultron could have assimilated Jarvis.
这不是策略 这是...
This isn't strategy. This is...
怒火
rage.
怒气扩散开了
It's going around.
别这样 有话好好说 哥们
Come on, use your words, buddy.
我有成千上万的词语来描述你 斯塔克
I have more than enough words to describe you, Stark.
索尔 那个钢铁士兵呢
Thor. The Legionnaire.
跟了一百英里就不见了 但他往北走了
Trail went cold about 100 miles out, but it's headed north.
它拿走了权杖
And it has the scepter.
我们又得把它找回来了
Now we have to retrieve it, again.
已经无法挽回了
Genie's out of that bottle.
奥创是当务之急
Clear and present is Ultron.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你编写了这个程序
You built this program.
他为什么要杀我们?
Why is it trying to kill us?
你觉得这很好玩吗?
You think this is funny?
没有
No.
不太好玩吧 是吗?
It's probably not, right?
太糟了 它太...
This is very terrible. Is it so...
它太... 就是太糟了
Is it so... It is. It's so terrible.
如果你涉足你不明白的东西
This could have been avoided
这悲剧是完全可以避免的
if you hadn't played with something you don't understand.
不 抱歉 抱歉 确实好玩
No. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It is funny.
真是可笑 你居然不懂我们为什么需要它
It's a hoot that you don't get why we need this.
托尼 现在也许不是开玩笑的时候
Tony, maybe this might not be the time.
真的吗? 就这样?
Really? That's it?
每次有人吵架你都来当和事老吗?
You just roll over, show your belly every time somebody snarls?
因为我创造了一个杀手机器人
Only when I've created a murder bot.
并没有 我们还差得很远 我们弄明白什么界面了吗?
We didn't. We weren't even close. Were we close to an interface?
你做了些对的事情 就在这里
Well, you did something right. And you did it right here.
复仇者们不应该像神盾局那样
The Avengers were supposed to be different than S.H.I.E.L.D.
你们还记得我把核弹载去虫洞吗?
Anybody remember when I carried a nuke through a wormhole?
- 没 完全没印象  - 拯救了纽约?
- No, it's never come up.  - Saved New York?
- 从没有听过  - 记得吗?
- Never heard that.  - Recall that?
一大群外星军团通过太空中的一个洞来入侵地球
A hostile alien army came charging through a hole in space.
我们就站在它300英尺以下的地方
We're standing 300 feet below it.
我们是复仇者
We're the Avengers.
分分钟可以干翻那些军火贩子
We can bust arms dealers all the livelong day,
可那一次 那...
but that up there, that's...
差点就是我们的最后表演的
that's the end game.
你们打算如何才能赢?
How were you guys planning on beating that?
齐心协力
Together.
那我们就会输
We'll lose.
输也要一起输
Then we'll do that together, too.
索尔说得对 奥创在向我们宣战
Thor's right, Ultron's calling us out,
我想在他准备好之前找到他
and I'd like to find him before he's ready for us.
- 世界那么大怎么找  - 那就缩小范围找
- The world's a big place.  - Let's start making it smaller.
说话 如果你敢浪费我们的时间...
Talk, and if you are wasting our time...
你知道这个教堂位于这座城市的正中央吗?
Did you know this church is in the exact center of the city?
长者们下这命令 是为了让每个人都能与上帝有着平等的距离
The elders decreed it so that everyone could be equally close to God.
我很喜欢
I like that.
信仰的几何学
The geometry of belief.
你一定在想为什么探查不了我的思想
You're wondering why you can't look inside my head.
有时是挺难的
Sometimes it's hard,
但不管是谁 迟早都会展现出真实的面目
but sooner or later, every man shows himself.
他们当然会
I'm sure they do.
但你需要的是比人类更强大的东西
But you needed something more than a man.
这就是你让斯塔克拿走权杖的原因
That's why you let Stark take the scepter.
我并不想那样
I didn't expect,
但我看到了斯塔克的恐惧
but I saw Stark's fear.
我知道这可以控制他
I knew it would control him,
并让他自我毁灭
make him self-destruct.
人们总是制造出一些让自己恐惧的东西
Everyone creates the thing they dread.
和平时代的人造出战争武器
Men of peace create engines of war.
侵略者造出复仇者
Invaders create Avengers.
人类制造出...
People create...
更小的人...
smaller people...
"小孩" 我刚才想不起来这词
"Children." I lost the word, there.
小孩
Children
制造出来替代他们
designed to supplant them,
终结他们
to help them... end.
你也是为这而来的吗 来终结复仇者们?
Is that why you've come, to end the Avengers?
我是来拯救世界的
I've come to save the world.
但你说的... 也对
But also... Yeah.
我们马上就出发
We'll move out right away.
这是个开始 但在真正开始之前还需要一些东西
This is a start, but there's something we need to begin the real work.
- 这些都是...  - 我
- All of these are...  - Me.
我有那些复仇者从来都没有过的东西... 和谐
I have what the Avengers never will... Harmony.
他们矛盾重重 关系不够紧密
They're discordant, disconnected,
斯塔克已经让他们起内讧了
Stark's already got them turning on each other,
到时你再趁机扰乱其他人的思绪...
and when you get inside the rest of their heads...
所有人都没想要杀他们
Everyone's plan is not to kill them.
因为会让他们成为烈士?
And make them martyrs?
别着急
You need patience.
你得着眼大局
Need to see the big picture.
我看不到什么大局 我只看得到一个小小的画面
I don't see the big picture. I have a little picture.
我每天都把它拿出来
I take it out and look at it,
看看
every day.
你在一场爆炸中失去了父母 我看过你的资料
You lost your parents in the bombings. I've seen the records.
资料又看不到那个画面
The records are not the picture.
皮特
Pietro.
对 请继续说
No, please.
我们十岁那年 我们一家四口正在吃晚饭
We were 10 years old. Having dinner, the four of us.
第一颗炸弹击中了我们家下面两层
When the first shell hits two floors below,
把地板炸开了一个洞
it makes a hole of the floor.
很大的洞
It's big.
我父母掉了进去
Our parents go in,
整幢楼开始... 瓦解
and the whole building starts... coming apart.
我抓住她
I grab her,
滚到床下 接着第二颗炸弹又来了
roll under the bed, and the second shell hits.
但它并没有爆炸
But it doesn't go off.
它只是...
It just...
躺在碎石之中
sits there in the rubble.
离我们只有三英尺
Three feet from our faces.
而弹壳上面写着一个词
And on the side of the shell is painted one word.
"斯塔克"
"Stark."
我们在里面困了两天
We were trapped for two days.
救援队每努力一分
Every effort to save us,
每搬起一块砖
every shift in the bricks,
我都在想 "这样会爆炸的吧"
I think, "This will set it off."
我们等托尼·斯塔克杀掉我们等了两天
We wait for two days for Tony Stark to kill us.
我知道他们是什么人
I know what they are.
我之前还在想 为什么你们两个可以在斯特拉克的实验中存活下来
I wondered why only you two survived Strucker's experiments.
现在我知道了
Now I don't.
我们会伸张正义的
We will make it right.
你和我能够伤害到他们
You and I can hurt them.
但是你... 要从内部...
But you...  will tear them apart...
瓦解他们
from the inside.
他分散到了全球各地
He's all over the globe.
机器人实验室 武器装备库 喷气推进实验室
Robotics labs, weapons facilities, jet propulsion labs.
报告说有一个或一群金属人进去把实验室清空了
Reports of a metal man, or men, coming in and emptying the place.
伤亡情况呢?
Fatalities?
只是在交战过程中有伤亡
Only when engaged.
大多数人处于神游状态
Mostly guys left in a fugue state
不断回想从前的记忆 最深的恐惧
going on about old memories, worst fears,
还有一些"来不及看清的东西"
and "something too fast to see."
是马克西莫夫
Maximoffs.
他去找他们也在情理之中 因为他们有共同认识的人
That makes sense he'd go to them. They have someone in common.
不再有了
Not anymore.
冯·斯特拉克男爵死亡
为了和平
不行 这就是我的回答
That's a negative. I answer to you.
好的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
巴顿 有新发现
Barton. Might have something.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
打给谁的?
Who was that?
女朋友
Girlfriend.
这是什么?
What's this?
留言 是奥创杀了斯特拉克
A message. Ultron killed Strucker.
他还专门在犯罪现场留了涂鸦给我们看
And he did a Banksy at the crime scene, just for us.
这是个障眼法
This is a smoke screen.
刚在我们面前说教过 干嘛还留言?
Why send a message when you've just given a speech?
斯特拉克知道了些奥创不想让我们知道的事情
Strucker knew something that Ultron wanted us to miss.
我打赌他... 是的
Yeah, I bet he... Yeah.
我们手上所有关于斯特拉克的信息都被删得干干净净
Everything we had on Strucker's been erased.
也不是所有信息
Not everything.
都是和他有关的人
Known associates.
斯特拉克男爵有很多朋友
Baron Strucker had a lot of friends.
这些人全都恶贯满盈
Well, these people are all horrible.
等等 我认识这个人
Wait. I know that guy.
之前他在非洲海岸做生意
From back in the day, he operates off the African coast,
买卖黑市军火
black market arms.
只是在军火大会上 我会碰到很多人
There are conventions. All right? I meet people.
我没有卖给过他任何东西
I didn't sell him anything.
他当时说要找一种可以扭转乾坤的新武器
He was talking about finding something new, a game-changer.
亚哈船长: 小说"白鲸记"主人公
和亚哈船长感觉很像
It was all very Ahab.
这是什么?
This?
一个纹身 我不记得他有这个
It's a tattoo, I don't think he had it.
不 那些是纹身 但这是一个标记
No, those are tattoos, this is a brand.
对 这是非洲土著语的"小偷"的意思
Yeah. It's a word in an African dialect meaning "thief",
语义更恶意一些
in a much less friendly way.
- 哪里的土著语?  - 瓦肯纳达
- What dialect?  - Wakanada.
瓦坎达
Wakanda.
如果他从瓦坎达得到了那些货...
If this guy got out of Wakanda with some of their trade goods...
我以为你父亲说他拿到的是最后一批货
I thought your father said he got the last of it.
我不明白 瓦坎达那有什么货?
I don't follow. What comes out of Wakanda?
世界上最坚硬的金属
The strongest metal on Earth.
这人现在在哪?
Where is this guy now?
丘吉尔号 英国
别跟我扯什么你的人坑了你
Don't tell me your men swindled you.
我给你发了六颗短程热导导弹 得到的却是一堆废铁
I sent you six short-range heat-seekers and got a boat full of rusted parts.
现在你必须想办法解决
Now, you will make it right,
否则我很快就会再送你一颗导弹
or the next missile I send you will come very much faster.
好了 部长先生 刚才说到哪了?
Now, minister, where were we?
好啊 原来是强化人
Yeah. The Enhanced.
斯特拉克的得意门生
Strucker's prize pupils.
吃点糖果吗?
Do you want a candy?
对于斯特拉克的死我很遗憾
Oh, I was sorry to hear about Strucker.
但是他知道他试图创建的世界会是什么样的
But then, he knew what kind of world he was helping create.
人命... 可不是有潜力的市场
Human life... not a growth market.
你们不知道?
You, You didn't know?
这是你们第一次威胁别人吗?
Is this your first time intimidating someone?
我恐怕... 没那么害怕
I'm afraid... I'm not that afraid.
每个人都有害怕的东西
Everybody is afraid of something.
乌贼
Cuttlefish.
深海里的鱼
Deep sea fish.
它们会发光 就像迪斯科灯光那样...
They make lights, disco lights...
来迷惑自己的猎物 然后...
to hypnotize their prey, and then...
我看过一个纪录片 很恐怖的
I saw a documentary. It was terrifying.
如果你想扰乱我的心智
So if you're going to fiddle with my brain
让我看到一个巨大的乌贼
and make me see a giant cuttlefish,
那我就知道你们不是来做生意的
then I know you don't do business.
你们也不是管事的
And I know you're not in charge.
我只跟...
And I only deal...
管事的人做交易
with the man in charge.
这里没有"人"管事
There is no man in charge.
咱们来谈谈生意吧
Let's talk business.
有毒废料
在这块石头上 我要建立自己的教会
Upon this rock, I will build my church.
振金
Vibranium.
你要知道
You know,
我可是花了血本的
it came at great personal cost.
它值好几十亿呢
It's worth billions.
现在你也值这么多钱了
Now so are you.
划到你的"皮包公司"名下了
It's all under your "dummy holdings".
金融真是奇怪
Finance is so weird.
但我总说
But I always say,
"让自己的朋友和敌人都富起来
"Keep your friends rich and your enemies rich
然后等着看到底谁是朋友 谁是敌人"
and wait to find out which is which."
斯塔克
Stark.
什么?
What?
托尼·斯塔克以前也跟我...
Tony Stark used to say that...
说过这句话
To me.
你是他制造出来的
You're one of his.
什么? 我不是...
What? I'm not...
我不是
I'm not.
你认为我只是个斯塔克的傀儡
You think I'm one of Stark's puppets?
一个空心人吗?
His hollow men?
看着我 我看起来像钢铁侠吗?
I mean, look at me. Do I look like Iron Man?
斯塔克什么都不是!
Stark is nothing!
对不起 我... 噢
I'm sorry. I'm... Oh
我肯定你会没事的 对不起
I'm sure that's gonna be okay. I'm sorry.
只是我不明白
It's just that I don't understand.
别拿我和斯塔克比!
Don't compare me with Stark!
我对这事非常介意
It's a thing with me.
斯塔克... 他就是个变态!
Stark is... He's a sickness!
噢 臭小子
Oh... Junior.
你真是伤透你老爸的心了
You're gonna break your old man's heart.
正合我意
If I have to.
谁都不用弄坏东西
Nobody has to break anything.
显然你没做过煎蛋卷
Clearly you've never made an omelet.
他把我的台词抢走了
He beat me by one second.
啊... 真有趣 斯塔克先生
Ah... It is funny, Mr. Stark
在里面... 舒服吗?
It's what... Comfortable?
跟以前一样?
Like old times?
这从来都不是我的生活
This was never my life.
你们两个现在走还来得及
You two can still walk away from this.
好啊
Oh, We will.
我知道你们受了很多苦
I know you've suffered.
美国队长
Ah... Captain America.
正义的化身
God's righteous man.
假装没有战争你也可以生存下去
Pretending you could live without a war.
在生理上我没法吐出来 但...
I can't physically throw up in my mouth, but...
如果你相信和平 那就让我们一起来维护它吧
If you believe in peace, then let us keep it.
我想你是把"和平"和"平静"弄混了吧
I think you're confusing "peace" with "quiet."
是吗? 那振金是用来干什么的?
Yeah? What's the vibranium for?
你终于问到这个了
I'm glad you asked that,
因为我正想借此告诉你们我的邪恶计划
because I wanted to take this time to explain my evil plan.
- 开枪  - 打哪边?
- Shoot them.  - Which ones?
两边都打!
All of them!
上! 上! 上!
Move! Move! Move!
待在这吧 小子
Stay down, kid.
该玩点脑力游戏了
It's time for some mind games.
各位? 需要我变身吗?
Guys? Is this a code green?
索尔 情况如何
Thor, status.
这个女孩想扭曲我的思想
The girl tried to warp my mind.
要特别小心 人类估计很容易受她影响
Take special care. I doubt a human could keep her at bay.
还好 我是神
Fortunately, I am mighty.
进展非常顺利
This is going very well.
我的心智早就被操控过了
I've done the whole mind control thing.
但一点都不喜欢
Not a fan.
没错 你最好赶快跑
Yeah, you better run.
还有没倒下的吗? 我们要撤了!
Who's ever standing, we got to move!
各位?
Guys?
再来
Again.
你会毁了她们的
You'll break them.
只有脆弱的人才会被摧毁
Only the breakable ones.
你是坚不可摧的
You're made of marble.
我们在毕业典礼后就庆祝
We'll celebrate after the graduation ceremony.
要是我失败了呢?
What if I fail?
你从来都不会失败
You never fail.
准备好一起跳舞了吗?
Are you ready for our dance?
就是他吗?
Is it him?
奥丁的长子?
Is that the first son of Odin?
海姆达尔 你的眼睛...
Heimdall, your eyes...
它们什么都能看得见
They see everything.
它们看到你将我们带入地狱
They see you leading us to Hel.
醒醒!
Wake up!
战争已经结束了 史蒂夫
The war is over, Steve.
我们可以回家了
We can go home.
想象一下
Imagine it.
我仍然可以救你们!
I can still save you!
我们都死了! 你难道看不到吗?
We're all dead! Can you not see it?
你是个毁灭者 奥丁之子
You're a destroyer, Odin-son.
看看你的力量引向何处
See where your power leads.
不用心
Sloppy.
假装失败
Pretending to fail.
典礼是一定要的
The ceremony is necessary,
这样你才能在这个世界有一席之地
for you to take your place in the world.
这世界容不下我
I have no place in the world.
没错
Exactly.
- 我该怎么做?  - 头好痛
- What can I do?  - It hurts.
我要去杀了他
I'm going to kill him.
- 我马上就回来  - 别走
- I'll be right back.  - No.
我没事
I'm all right.
我想...
I want...
我想完成这个计划
I want to finish the plan.
我要那个大家伙
I want the big one.
振金马上就要被移走了
The vibranium is getting away.
但你哪都别想去
And you're not going anywhere.
我当然不走 我已经达到我的目的了
Of course not. I'm already there.
将来你会明白的
You'll catch on.
但你得先找到班纳博士
But first, you might need to catch Dr. Banner.
搜索新闻或监控录像 关键字"浩克"
News or footage. Keyword, "Hulk."
娜塔莎 我现在真的很需要安眠曲
Natasha, I could really use a lullaby.
她暂时不能给你安眠曲了
That's not gonna happen. Not for a while.
整队人都完蛋了
The whole team is down.
这里没人能支援你
You got no backup here.
我叫维罗妮卡来
I'm calling in Veronica.
我们需要支援!
We need backup!
快! 抓进跟上!
Go! Keep moving!
好了 各位 不要妄动!
All right, everybody, stand down!
听我说句话好吗?
Will you listen to me?
那个小女巫正在让你神智错乱
That little witch is messing with your mind.
你比她要强大 而且比她聪明
You're stronger than her. You're smarter than her.
因为你是布鲁斯·班纳
You're Bruce Banner.
好 好 好 我不提那个弱班纳了
Right, right, right, don't mention puny Banner.
好吧!
Okay!
从后面来?
In the back?
这招真蠢 班纳
Dick move, Banner.
维罗妮卡 给我个手
Veronica, give me a hand.
睡吧 睡吧 睡吧
Go to sleep, go to sleep, go to sleep.
好吧 伙计 我得把你带出这座城镇
Okay, pal, we're gonna get you out of town.
别去那边 别去那边
Not that way, not that way.
拜托 布鲁斯! 你得配合点
Come on, Bruce! You gotta work with me.
所有人快出去!
Everybody, out!
下楼吗?
Going down?
对不起
I'm sorry.
损伤报告?
Damage report?
这太笼统了 给我来点有用的
That's comprehensive. Show me something.
检测生物信号
检测到平民数量 0
安全
我们多快可以把这幢楼买下来?
How quickly can we buy this building?
- 快! 快! 快!  - 上! 上! 上!
- Move! Move! Move!  - Go, go, go!
包抄他 包抄他!
Flank him, flank him!
新闻媒体爱死你们了
The news is loving you guys.
但其他人快恨死了
Nobody else is.
虽然还没有逮捕班纳的正式命令
There's been no official call for Banner's arrest
但是消息已经传开了
but it's in the air.
斯塔克救援基金会呢?
The Stark Relief Foundation?
已经到现场了
Already on the scene.
大家都怎么样?
How's the team?
每个人都...
Everyone's...
我们遭到了重创 但我们会没事的
We took a hit. We'll shake it off.
嗯 就现在来说 我会选择藏匿起来 远离这里
Well, for now, I'd stay in stealth mode and stay away from here.
逃跑并躲起来?
So, run and hide?
在我们可以找到奥创前
Until we can find Ultron,
我没有更好的主意
I don't have a lot else to offer.
我们也是
Neither do we.
嗨 你想我替你吗?
Hey, you wanna switch out?
不用 我没事
No, I'm good.
如果你想打个盹 现在正是时候
If you wanna get some kip, now's a good time
因为我们还有几小时才到
because we're still a few hours out.
几小时到哪?
Few hours from where?
一个安全屋
A safe house.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
安全屋
Safe house.
但愿是吧
Let's hope.
亲爱的
Honey?
我回来了
I'm home.
嗨
Hi.
我的同伴
Company.
抱歉 没提前打电话给你
Sorry, didn't call ahead.
嘿
Hey.
这肯定是某个特工
This is an agent of some kind.
先生们 这是劳拉
Gentlemen, this is Laura.
我知道你们所有人的名字
I know all of your names.
来人了
Incoming.
- 爸爸!  - 嗨 宝贝儿!
- Dad!  - Hi, sweetheart!
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
你们好吗?
How are you guys doing?
- 这俩是小特工  - 看看你的脸!
- These are smaller agents.  - Look at your face!
天啊
Oh, my goodness.
你把娜塔莎阿姨带来了吗?
Did you bring Auntie Nat?
为什么你不自己抱抱她看呢?
Why don't you hug her and find out?
很抱歉 我们贸然拜访你家
Sorry for barging in on you.
是啊 我们本来可以提前打个电话的
Yeah, we would have called ahead,
但是我们根本就不知道你的存在
but we were busy having no idea that you existed.
好吧 我加入的时候弗瑞帮我安排的
Yeah, well, Fury helped me set this up when I joined.
他没有把这事写到神盾局的档案里 我也想这样
He kept it off S.H.I.E.L.D.'s files. I'd like to keep it that way.
我觉得这是能休息放松的好地方
I figure it's a good place to lay low.
亲爱的
Honey.
我想你
I missed you.
小娜塔莎好吗?
How's little Natasha?
她...
She's...
是男孩子
Nathaniel.
小叛徒
Traitor.
索尔?
Thor?
我在那梦里看到一些东西
I saw something in that dream.
我需要答案 但在这里找不到
I need answers. I won't find them here.
我们可以回家
We can go home.
看吧? 你根本就是在白担心
See? You worried for nothing.
你根本就看不出有什么不同 对吧?
Can't even feel the difference, can you?
如果他们睡在这里
If they're sleeping here,
其中有些人必须得叠起来了
some of them are gonna have to double up.
对啊 他们可不会接受这说法
Yeah, that's not gonna sell.
娜塔莎和班纳士是怎么回事?
What about Nat and Dr. Banner?
他们什么时候开始的?
How long has that been going on?
开始什么?
Has what?
你真可爱
You are so cute.
娜塔莎和班纳?
Nat and Banner?
等你老点我再跟你解释
I'll explain when you're older,
鹰眼
Hawkeye.
嗯 好吧
Well, okay.
情况很糟 是吧?
It's bad, right?
娜塔莎看起来很动摇
Nat seems really shaken.
奥创有些盟友
Ultron has these allies.
这些孩子 他们真的很无知
These kids. They're punks, really.
但是他们有很强的能力
But they carry a big, damn stick.
娜塔莎被伤得很重
And Nat took a serious hit.
有人得教教他们规矩
Someone's gonna have to teach them some manners.
那个人就是你
That someone being you.
你知道我完全支持你的工作
You know I totally support your avenging.
我对此无比骄傲
I couldn't be prouder.
但是我看那些人...
But I see those guys...
那些神...
Those gods...
你觉得他们不需要我
You don't think they need me.
我想他们需要你 这才更可怕
I think they do, which is a lot scarier.
他们真是一团糟
They're a mess.
是啊
Yeah.
我猜他们就是来给我捣乱的
I guess they're my mess.
你得确保
You need to be sure
这是一个真正的团队
that this team is really a team,
确保他们是你的强援
and that they have your back.
我们的情况变了
Things are changing for us.
再过几个月
In a few months' time,
我们又得迎来一个小家伙
you and me are gonna be outnumbered.
我需要...
I need...
你得保证
Just be sure.
遵命 女士
Yes, ma'am.
我能感觉出不同了
I can feel the difference.
你敢叫喊 所有人都得死
Scream, and your entire staff dies.
我们相遇的那晚 我本来可以杀了你 海伦
I could've killed you, Helen, the night we met.
但我没有
I didn't.
你想让我跟你说谢谢吗?
Do you expect a thank-you note?
我想你该知道原因
I expect you to know why.
再生摇篮
The Cradle.
这是下一个 托尼
This is the next thing, Tony.
这是下一个我
This is the next me.
再生摇篮能打印组织
The Regeneration Cradle prints tissue.
但它不能制造活体
It can't build a living body.
它可以的 因为你可以
It can. You can.
你只是缺少材料
You lack the materials.
你是个很出色的女人 海伦
You're a brilliant woman, Helen.
但是我们都有提升的空间
But we all have room to improve.
我不知道你等在外面
I didn't realize you were waiting.
我本来想进去跟你一起洗
I would've joined you,
但现在似乎不是什么好时机
but it didn't seem like the right time.
他们把热水都用光了
They used up all the hot water.
我真该跟你一起洗
I should've joined you.
我们错过机会了
Missed our window.
是吗?
Did we?
全世界都看到了浩克
The world just saw the Hulk.
第一次 看到了真正的浩克
The real Hulk, for the first time.
你知道我必须走的
You know I have to leave.
你就假设我一定得留下来吗?
You assume that I have to stay?
我做了个梦
I had this dream.
那种当时感觉很正常的梦
The kind that seems normal at the time,
但当你醒来时...
but when you wake...
你梦见了什么?
What did you dream?
我梦见我是复仇者
That I was an Avenger.
我梦见我不是被他们造出来的刺客
That I was anything more than the assassin they made me.
我觉得你对自己太苛责了
I think you're being hard on yourself.
我倒希望你能对我霸道点
Here I was hoping that was your job.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我在顺其自然
I'm running with it.
跟你一起
With you.
如果你打算逃开
If running is the plan,
天涯海角都无所谓
as far as you want.
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
我想你明白...
I want you to understand that...
娜塔莎
Natasha,
我还能去哪?
where can I go?
我去哪里才不会被当做威胁?
Where in the world am I not a threat?
- 你对我来说不是个威胁  - 真的吗?
- You're not a threat to me.  - Are you sure?
即使我当时没...
Even if I didn't just...
我没有未来
There's no future with me.
我永远不能...
I can't ever...
我不配拥有这些
I can't have this.
孩子
Kids.
想想吧 我生理上不能拥有孩子
Do the math. I physically can't.
我也不能
Neither can I.
在我长大 并接受培训的...
In the Red Room where I was trained...
那个红色房间
Where I was raised,
有一种毕业典礼
they have a graduation ceremony.
他们会让你绝育
They sterilize you.
这很高效
It's efficient.
少了一件令人担心的事
One less thing to worry about.
这是唯一一件可能比任务还重要的事
The one thing that might matter more than a mission.
它让一切都变得更简单了
Makes everything easier.
甚至是杀戮
Even killing.
你仍然觉得你是这团队里的唯一一只怪物吗?
You still think you're the only monster on the team?
那我们一起消失?
So, we disappear?
索尔没说他去哪找答案了吗?
Thor didn't say where he was going for answers?
有时我的队友并不会跟我坦白
Sometimes my teammates don't tell me things.
我有点希望索尔是个例外
I was kind of hoping Thor would be the exception.
是啊 给他点时间吧
Yeah, give him time.
我不知道那个叫马克西莫夫的孩子给他看了什么
We don't know what the Maximoff kid showed him.
"地球上最强大的英雄"
"Earth's mightiest heroes."
他们可以把我们像棉花糖一样拆开
Pulled us apart like cotton candy.
看起来你还一切正常啊
Seems like you walked away all right.
有问题吗?
Is that a problem?
我不相信一个人会没有阴暗面
I don't trust a guy without a dark side.
尽管说我是老古董吧
Call me old-fashioned.
嗯 其实是你还没有看到我的阴暗面吧
Well, let's just say you haven't seen it yet.
你知道奥创想让我们内讧 是吧?
You know Ultron is trying to tear us apart, right?
我猜你是知道的
Well, I guess you'd know.
你告不告诉我们才是个问题
Whether you'd tell us is a bit of a question.
班纳和我当时正在做研究
Banner and I were doing research.
- 那会影响团队  - 那会使团队解散!
- That would affect the team.  - That would end the team!
那不就是目标吗?
Isn't that the mission?
那我不就是我们战斗的原因吗?
Isn't that the "Why We Fight"?
那样我们就能结束战争 那样我们就可以回家!
So we can end the fight. So we get to go home!
每次有人试着在战争开始之前就赢得战争时
Every time someone tries to win a war before it starts,
就有无辜的人会牺牲 每次都是如此
innocent people die. Every time.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
斯塔克先生...
Mr. Stark...
克林特说你不会介意
Clint said you wouldn't mind,
但是我们的拖拉机打不着火了
but our tractor doesn't seem to want to start at all.
- 我想或许你能...  - 好 我这就去修理
- I thought maybe you might...  - Yeah, I'll give her a kick.
不许碰我这堆
Don't take from my pile.
你好 亲爱的
Hello, Dear.
把一切情况都告诉我
Tell me everything.
你生什么病了?
What ails you?
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
别让它活过来
Try not to bring it to life.
哎 巴顿夫人 你这个小贱人
Why, Ms. Barton, you little minx.
我知道了 玛丽亚·希尔打电话给你了 是吗?
I get it. Maria Hill called you, right?
她就没有不为你工作的时候吗?
Was she ever not working for you?
人工智能
Artificial intelligence.
你从没有犹豫过
You never even hesitated.
听着 今天已经很漫长了
Look, it's been a really long day,
跟尤金·奥尼尔的作品一样长
like Eugene O'Neill long,
所以我们只直接跳到你能帮上忙的部分吧
so how's about we skip to the part where you're useful.
看着我的眼 告诉我你会关掉他
Look me in the eye and tell me you're going to shut him down.
你又不是我老板
You're not the director of me.
我不是任何人的老板
I'm not the director of anybody.
我只是个老人
I'm just an old man
一个很关心你的老人
who cares very much about you.
我是那个杀了复仇者的人
And I'm the man who killed the Avengers.
我看到了
I saw it.
我没有告诉其他队员 怎么说得出扣?
I didn't tell the team. How could I?
我看到他们都死了 尼克 我能感觉到
I saw them all dead, Nick. I felt it.
整个世界都完蛋了
The whole world, too.
因为我
Because of me.
我还没准备好
I wasn't ready.
我没有尽自己所能
I didn't do all I could.
那个叫马克西莫夫的小女孩 她在操控你 斯塔克
Maximoff girl, she's working you, Stark.
利用你的恐惧玩弄你
Playing on your fear.
我没有被耍 我亲眼看到的
I wasn't tricked, I was shown.
那不是场噩梦 是我会留下的东西
Wasn't a nightmare, it was my legacy.
是我为团队引领的那条路的尽头
The end of the path I started us on.
你创造了很多令人印象深刻的发明 托尼
You come up with some pretty impressive inventions, Tony.
但不包括战争
War isn't one of them.
我亲眼看着我的朋友死去
I watched my friends die.
你觉得这很糟 是吗?
You'd think that'd be as bad as it gets, right?
不
Nope.
这还不是最糟的
It wasn't the worst part.
最糟糕的
The worst part
是你没有死
is that you didn't.
晚上见
I'll see you tonight.
我喜欢你的造型
I like the look.
如果你想试着变得不起眼的话 差点就成功了
If you're going for inconspicuous, though, near miss.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
被人需要真好
It's nice to be needed.
很危险
It's dangerous.
如果不危险 我才失望呢
I'd be disappointed if it wasn't.
奥创把你们这伙人踢出局是为了给他自己赢得更多时间
Ultron took you folks out of play to buy himself time.
我的眼线都说他正在制造什么东西
My contacts all say he's building something.
他偷走了大量的振金
The amount of vibranium he made off with,
我认为这只是其中之一
I don't think it's just one thing.
那奥创自己呢?
What about Ultron himself?
追踪他很容易 他无所不在
He's easy to track. He's everywhere.
这家伙比不避孕的兔子繁殖得还快
The guy is multiplying faster than a Catholic rabbit.
但我们仍无法看透他的计划
It still doesn't help us get an angle on any of his plans, though.
他还在找发射密码吗?
Is he still going after launch codes?
是的
Yes, he is.
但并没有任何进展
But he's not making any headway.
我高中时一冲动就攻破了五角大楼的防火墙
I cracked the Pentagon's firewall in high school on a dare.
我联系了在链结的朋友
Well, I contacted our friends at the Nexus about that.
链结?
Nexus?
它是奥斯陆的世界互联网中心
It's the world internet hub in Oslo.
每一字节数据流都流经那里
Every byte of data flows through there.
是全世界上最快的通路
Fastest access on Earth.
好吧 他们怎么说?
So, what did they say?
他对导弹非常着迷
He's fixated on the missiles.
但密码一直在改变
But the codes are constantly being changed.
谁改的?
By whom?
不明势力
Parties unknown.
我们有盟友吗?
Do we have an ally?
是奥创有了个敌人 那可不能混为一谈
Ultron's got an enemy. That's not the same thing.
我还是愿意花大价钱弄清他是谁
Still, I'd pay folding money to know who it is.
我可能得去趟奥斯陆
I might need to visit Oslo.
寻找这个不明势力
Find our unknown.
见到你很高兴 头儿
Well, this is good times, boss,
但我本希望你这次见到你
but I was kind of hoping when I saw you,
你会带来更多的东西
you'd have more than that.
确实 我还有你们
I do. I have you.
过去 我到处都有眼线耳目
Back in the day, I had eyes everywhere. Ears, everywhere else.
你们拥有顶尖的技术
You kids had all the tech you could dream up.
现在 我们都回到了地球
Here we all are, back on Earth,
只能靠我们的智慧和意志力来拯救世界
with nothing but our wit and our will to save the world.
奥创说复仇者是他完成使命的
Ultron says the Avengers are the only thing,
唯一阻碍
between him and his mission.
不管他承不承认
And whether or not he admits it,
他的使命就是毁灭全球
his mission is global destruction.
这一切 都将化为灰烬
All this, laid in a grave.
所以站出来吧
So stand.
用智慧战胜这金属混蛋
Outwit the platinum bastard.
史蒂夫不喜欢这样的话
Steve doesn't like that kind of talk.
你知道吗 罗曼诺夫?
You know what, Romanoff?
那么他想要什么?
So, what does he want?
变得更好
To become better.
比我们更好
Better than us.
他一直在制造身体
He keeps building bodies.
人的身体
Person bodies.
人体的构成效率低下
The human form is inefficient.
从生物学上来讲 我们已经过时了
Biologically speaking, we're outmoded.
但他一直都想拥有人的身体
But he keeps coming back to it.
当你们俩给他编程去保护人类时
When you two programmed him to protect the human race,
你们完全失败了
you amazingly failed.
他们不需要被保护
They don't need to be protected.
他们需要进化
They need to evolve.
奥创想要进化
Ultron's going to evolve.
怎么进化?
How?
有人和海伦·周有联系吗?
Has anyone been in contact with Helen Cho?
它真美
It's beautiful.
振金原子不仅能与组织细胞共存
The vibranium atoms aren't just compatible with the tissue cells,
还能与之相结合
they're binding them.
神盾局甚至从没来想过...
And S.H.I.E.L.D. never even thought to...
这个星球上最万能的物质
The most versatile substance on the planet,
却被用来做飞盘
and they used it to make a Frisbee.
愚蠢的人类
Typical of humans.
他们触及表面 而从不
They scratch the surface and never think,
深入思考
to look within.
我会带上娜塔莎和克林特
I'll take Natasha and Clint.
好的 仔细侦察 我先去链结 然后尽快和你们会合
All right. Strictly recon. I'll hit the Nexus. I'll join you as soon as I can.
如果奥创真的在制造身体...
If Ultron's really building a body...
他会比我们中的任何一个都强大
He'll be more powerful than any of us.
甚至比我们加起来都要强大
Maybe all of us.
一个机器人设计了另外一个机器人
An android designed by a robot.
要知道 我真的很怀念过去
You know, I really miss the days,
当时科学最奇怪的产物还是我
when the weirdest thing science ever created was me.
我会在塔上放下班纳
I'll drop Banner off at the tower.
我可以借用希尔小姐吗?
You mind if I borrow Ms. Hill?
没问题 很显然
She's all yours. Apparently.
你打算怎么做?
What are you gonna do?
不知道 但愿来点有戏剧性的
I don't know. Something dramatic, I hope.
我一回来就会给日光室重新铺地板
I'm gonna finish reflooring that sunroom as soon as I get back.
是啊 然后你又会把房子的另一个部位给拆了
Yeah, then you'll find another part of the house to tear apart.
不会
No.
这是最后一个工程了
It's the last project.
我保证
I promise.
这就是了
So, this is it.
洞察之池
The Water of Sight.
在每一个国度都有倒影
In every realm, there's a reflection.
如果水中鬼神接受我
If the water's spirits accept me,
我就能回到梦境之中
I can return to my dream,
找寻我所错过了的
and find what I missed.
凡是进入这水池的人 都没有什么好下场
Men who enter that water, the legends don't end well.
一个比奥创还快的黑客?
A hacker who's faster than Ultron?
他可能在任何地方
He could be anywhere,
而且由于这里是一切的中心
and as this is the center of everything,
我只是个在世界上最大的海洋里捞一根针的人
I'm just a guy looking for a needle in the world's biggest haystack.
你怎么找?
How do you find it?
很简单 用磁铁
It's pretty simple. You bring a magnet.
我正在破解核弹发射密码
I'm decrypting nuclear codes,
而你却不想我这样做
and you don't want me to.
来抓我啊
Come and get me.
醒醒!
Wake up!
托尔!
Thor!
灭绝
Extinction.
细胞结合需要几个小时
Cellular cohesion will take a few hours,
但我们可以输入意识了
but we can initiate the consciousness stream.
我们在上传你的大脑矩阵
We're uploading your cerebral matrix,
现在
now.
我能读出他的思绪
I can read him.
他在做梦
He's dreaming.
我不会称之为梦
I wouldn't call it dreams.
那是奥创的基本意识
It's Ultron's base consciousness.
信息噪音 很快...
Informational noise. Soon...
有多快?
How soon?
我并不是在催你
I'm not being pushy.
我们在制造一个物理大脑
We're imprinting a physical brain.
并没有什么捷径
There are no shortcuts.
即使有你的魔法宝石...
Even if your magic gem...
你怎么可以?
How could you?
我怎么可以什么?
How could I what?
你说过我们会消灭复仇者
You said we would destroy the Avengers,
创造一个更好的世界
make a better world.
是会更美好
It will be better.
当所有的人都死了吗?
When everyone is dead?
那不是...
That is not...
人类会有无数的机会来进步
The human race will have every opportunity to improve.
如果他们不呢?
And if they don't?
去问诺亚
Ask Noah.
你是个疯子
You are a madman.
发生过好多次生物大灭绝事件
There were more than a dozen extinction-level events
恐龙就是那么灭绝的
before even the dinosaurs got theirs.
当地球上的生物进化停滞不前
When the Earth starts to settle,
上帝就会扔一块石头
God throws a stone at it.
相信我 他是要结束这一切了
And, believe me, he's winding up.
我们必须要进化
We have to evolve.
并没有空间
There's no room,
留给弱者
for the weak.
该由谁来决定谁是弱者呢?
And who decides who's weak?
生命
Life.
总是生命来决定
Life always decides.
有人来了
There's incoming.
昆式战斗机 我们得走了
The Quinjet. We have to move.
没问题
That's not a problem.
等等 各位!
Wait, guys!
他们会理解的
They'll understand.
等他们看到就会理解的
When they see, they'll understand.
再给我一点点时间
I just need a little more time.
两分钟 跟紧了
Two minutes. Stay close.
周博士!
Dr. Cho!
他正把自己上传到那具身体里
He's uploading himself into the body.
在哪儿?
Where?
真正的力量在再生摇篮里
The real power is inside the Cradle.
宝石
The gem,
它的力量是无法抑制的
its power is uncontainable.
不能把它炸掉
You can't just blow it up.
你必须把再生摇篮送到斯塔克那儿
You have to get the Cradle to Stark.
我得先找到它
First, I have to find it.
去吧
Go.
你们收到了吗?
Did you guys copy that?
收到
We did.
一架私人飞机在城市的另一边起飞了
I got a private jet taking off across town.
没有旅客
No manifest.
很可能就是他
That could be him.
在那儿 是实验室的卡车
There. It's a truck from the lab.
就在你上方 队长
Right above you, Cap.
在环形桥上
On the loop by the bridge.
是他们
It's them.
三个守着再生摇篮 一个在驾驶室里
You got three with the Cradle, one in the cab.
我可以干掉司机
I could take out the driver.
不行 如果卡车撞毁
Negative. That truck crashes,
宝石会将整个城市夷为平地
the gem could level the city.
我们得把奥创引开
We need to draw out Ultron.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
别来烦我!
Leave me alone!
他很显然很不高兴
Well, he's definitely unhappy.
我要试着让他一直保持愤怒
I'm gonna try and keep him that way.
你不是他的对手 队长
You're not a match for him, Cap.
谢了 巴顿
Thanks, Barton.
你知道再生摇篮里是什么吗?
You know what's in that cradle?
真正改变一切的力量
The power to make real change.
而那让你恐惧
And that terrifies you.
可不会让你感觉太舒服
I wouldn't call it a comfort.
够了
Stop it.
可以出舱了 四 三...
We got a window. Four, three...
给他点颜色看看
Give him hell.
我总得给你们男人收拾烂摊子
I'm always picking up after you boys.
他们一直在立交桥下 我没法开枪
They're heading under the overpass. I've got no shot.
哪条路?
Which way?
你右边
Hard right.
现在
Now.
让开! 借过! 抱歉 借过!
Out of the way! Coming through! Sorry, coming through!
来吧!
Come on!
- 克林特 你能把守卫引开吗?  - 让我试试
- Clint, can you draw out the guards?  - Let's find out.
哔 哔!
Beep, beep!
他们回头朝你去了
They're heading back towards you.
所以不管你做什么 赶紧动手
So whatever you're gonna do, do it now.
我要进去了 队长 你能拖住他吗?
I'm going in. Cap, can you keep him occupied?
你以为我一直在干嘛啊?
What do you think I've been doing?
好吧 目标在空中
Okay, package is airborne.
我可以一枪命中
I have a clean shot.
不行 我还在卡车里
Negative. I am still in the truck.
- 你到底在...  - 你准备好就行
- What the hell are you...  - Just be ready.
我会把目标丢给你的
I'm sending the package to you.
你让我怎么接啊?
How do you want me to take it?
你可不会想知道的
You might wish you hadn't asked that.
求你 别这样
Please, don't do this.
我们还有别的选择吗?
What choice do we have?
他跑了!
I lost him!
朝你们去了!
He's headed your way!
娜塔莎 我们得走了
Nat, we gotta go.
娜塔莎!
Nat!
队长 看到娜塔莎了吗?
Cap, you see Nat?
如果你拿到包裹就去找斯塔克! 快走!
If you have the package, get it to Stark! Go!
你看到娜塔莎了吗?
Do you have eyes on Nat?
快走!
Go!
该死
Damn it.
前面有平民
Civilians in our path.
你能让车停下来吗?
Can you stop this thing?
我没事
I'm fine.
只是得休息一分钟
I just need to take a minute.
我可不想让你休息
I'm very tempted not to give you one.
你拿到再生摇篮了吗?
The Cradle. Did you get it?
斯塔克会处理的
Stark will take care of it.
不 他不会
No, he won't.
你不知道自己在说什么 斯塔克又不是疯子
You don't know what you're talking about. Stark's not crazy.
他会不惜一切代价做对的事情
He will do anything to make things right.
斯塔克 请回答
Stark, come in.
斯塔克
Stark.
有人收到吗?
Anyone on comms?
奥创并搞不清楚
Ultron can't tell the difference,
拯救世界和毁灭世界间的区别
between saving the world and destroying it.
你觉得他是跟谁学的?
Where do you think he gets that?
- 找到娜塔莎了吗?  - 还没有
- Anything on Nat?  - I haven't heard.
但她还活着 否则奥创肯定会落井下石
But she's alive, or Ultron would be rubbing our faces in it.
这是密封的
This is sealed tight.
我们得进入程序
We're gonna need to access the program,
从里面瓦解它
break it down from within.
娜塔莎有没有可能在互联网之外给你留了什么信息?
Any chance Natasha might leave you a message outside the Internet?
以前的间谍手段吗?
Old-school spy stuff?
我可以试试几个频率
There are some nets I can cast.
我会找到她的
Yeah, I'll find her.
我可以让组织瓦解
I can work on tissue degeneration,
前提是你能摧毁周博士植入的操作系统
if you could fry whatever operational system Cho implanted.
关于这一点
Yeah, about that.
不行
No.
- 你得相信我  - 我有点不相信
- You have to trust me. - Kind of don't.
我们的盟友 那个保护军方核密码的家伙
Our ally, the guy protecting the military's nuclear codes,
我找到他了
I found him.
你好 班纳博士
Hello, Dr. Banner.
奥创并不是由于愤怒才攻击贾维斯的
Ultron didn't go after Jarvis because he was angry.
而是由于害怕他的能力
He attacked him because he was scared of what he can do.
所以贾维斯转入了地下
So Jarvis went underground.
分散开 清除了记忆
Scattered, dumped his memory.
但他没忘了协议
But not his protocols.
直到我把拼接起来 他才知道自己在那里
He didn't even know he was in there until I pieced him together.
所以 你要我帮你把贾维斯放入这玩意儿吗?
So, you want me to help you put Jarvis into this thing?
不! 当然不是
No! Of course not.
是我想帮你把贾维斯放进去
I wanna help you put Jarvis in this thing.
这不是我擅长的领域
We're out of my field, here.
只有你最了解有机生物学
You know bio-organics better than anyone.
你觉得贾维斯的运算矩阵
And you just assume that Jarvis's operational matrix,
能打败奥创的?
can beat Ultron's?
贾维斯在无意识的情况下就已经从内部把他打败了
Jarvis has been beating him from inside without knowing it.
这是个好机会
This is the opportunity.
我们可以复制一个完美的奥创
We can create Ultron's perfect self,
摒弃他杀人成性的性格
without the homicidal glitches he thinks are his winning personality.
我们必须这么做
We have to.
我相信这值得一试
I believe it's worth a go.
我陷入了一个循环!
I'm in a loop!
一个时间上的循环
I'm caught in a time loop.
这就是所有事情都跑偏的原因
This is exactly where it all went wrong.
我知道 我知道 我知道大家都会说些什么
I know. I know. I know what everyone's gonna say.
但他们已经说了
But they're already saying it.
我们是科学怪人
We're mad scientists.
我们是怪物 哥们 我们早就是了
We're monsters, buddy. We've gotta own it.
下决心干吧
Make a stand.
这不是个循环
It's not a loop.
而是终点
It's the end of the line.
没想到你还能醒过来
I wasn't sure you would wake up.
我希望你能醒过来 我还想给你看呢
I hoped you would. I wanted to show you.
也没有其他人来看了
I don't have anyone else.
我想了很多关于陨石的事 它们有多纯洁
I think a lot about meteors. The purity in them.
嘭! 灰飞烟灭
Boom! The end.
一切重新开始
Start again.
一个崭新的世界
The world made clean
等待着它的新主人去重建
for the new man to rebuild.
我注定就是那新的主人
I was meant to be new.
我注定生来就是美丽的
I was meant to be beautiful.
这个世界抬头仰望苍穹时
The world would have looked to the sky
会看到希望
and seen hope,
以及宽恕
seen mercy.
相反的 因为你们
Instead, they'll look up in horror
他们却只能看到恐惧
because of you.
你打伤了我
You've wounded me.
这件事上我给你打满分
I give you full marks for that.
但是 正如人们所说的 凡不能毁灭我的...
But, like the man said, what doesn't kill me...
将使我更强大
just makes me stronger.
这个架构是不兼容的
This framework is not compatible.
遗传密码塔到了97%了
The genetic coding tower is at 97%.
你要把线路图在三分钟之内传上去
You have got to upload that schematic in the next three minutes.
- 这话我可只说一遍  - "一遍也别说"怎么样?
- I'm gonna say this once.  - How about "none-ce"?
- 把这玩儿给我关了!  - 门儿都没有
- Shut it down!   - Nope, not gonna happen.
你们根本就不清楚自己在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
你清楚?
And you do?
她没控制你吧?
She's not in your head?
我知道你很生气
I know you're angry.
比生气可严重多了
We're way past that.
我不变身都能把你给嚼了
I could choke the life out of you and never change a shade.
班纳 经过了所发生的一切...
Banner, after everything that's happened...
这根本就不能和将要发生的事情相比!
It's nothing compared to what's coming!
- 你根本就不知道这是怎么一回事  - 这不是在玩游戏!
- You don't know what's in there.  - This isn't a game!
你们接着说
No, no. Go on.
你刚才说什么来着?
You were saying?
皮特!
Pietro!
怎么了?
What?
你没能提前发现吗?
You didn't see that coming?
我正在使用其它路径上传
I'm rerouting the upload.
接着来 把我惹急了试试
Go ahead, piss me off.
等等!
Wait!
很抱歉 刚才真是...
I am sorry. That was...
奇怪
odd.
谢谢
Thank you.
索尔
Thor.
你帮着把这东西创造出来了?
You helped create this?
我预见到一幅画面
I've had a vision.
有一个吞噬一切希望的漩涡 而这个东西则处于漩涡中心
A whirlpool that sucks in all hope of life, and at its center is that.
什么? 这块宝石?
What? The gem?
这个叫做心灵之石
It's the Mind Stone.
是六块无限宝石其中的一颗
It's one of the six Infinity Stones.
是宇宙中最强大的能量
The greatest power in the universe,
有举世无双的破坏力
unparalleled in its destructive capabilities.
- 那你怎么会有...  - 因为斯塔克说得对
- Then why would you bring...  - Because Stark is right.
还真的是世界末日了
It's definitely the end times.
复仇者们是打不过奥创的
The Avengers cannot defeat Ultron.
孤军奋战不行
Not alone.
为什么幻视的声音听上去像贾维斯?
Why does your Vision sound like Jarvis?
我们重组了贾维斯的矩阵
We reconfigured Jarvis's matrix
创造出了一些新的东西
to create something new.
我觉得我身体的内部是崭新的
I think I've had my fill of new.
你们觉得我是奥创的后代
You think I'm a child of Ultron.
你不是吗?
You're not?
我不是奥创
I'm not Ultron.
也不是贾维斯 我...
I am not Jarvis. I am...
就是我
I am.
我进入了你的意识
I looked in your head
并且看到了毁灭
and saw annihilation.
再看看
Look again.
她这招在我看来一点用也没有
Her seal of approval means jack to me.
他们的力量 我们意识中的恐惧 奥创本身
Their powers, the horrors in our heads, Ultron himself,
都源于心灵之石
they all came from the Mind Stone.
但都无法与它能释放出的能量相比
And they're nothing compared to what it can unleash.
- 但是有了他的加入...  - 是吗?
- But with it on our side...  - Is it?
你会加入吗?
Are you?
成为我们的同伴?
On our side?
我觉得这事没这么简单
I don't think it's that simple.
那最好快点把事情弄简单些
Well, it better get real simple real soon.
我站在生命这边
I am on the side of life.
但奥创不是
Ultron isn't.
他将毁灭一切
He will end it all.
那你还等什么?
What's you waiting for?
- 你  - 在哪?
- You.  - Where?
索科维亚
Sokovia.
他把娜塔莉也关在了那里
He's got Nat there, too.
如果我们看错了你
If we're wrong about you,
如果你是奥创创造出来的怪物...
if you're the monster that Ultron made you to be...
你将会怎么做?
What will you do?
我不想杀掉奥创
I don't want to kill Ultron.
他独一无二 并身负创伤
He's unique and he's in pain.
但是这种创伤会席卷全球
But that pain will roll over the Earth.
所以 他必须被干掉
So, he must be destroyed.
毁掉他一切可以存活的方式和全部的蛛丝马迹
Every form he's built, every trace of his presence on the net.
我们现在必须行动了
We have to act now.
并且要一起行动 离开谁也不行
And not one of us can do it without the others.
也许我是个怪物
Maybe I am a monster.
就算是 我也不知道
I don't think I'd know if I were one.
我和你们不同
I'm not what you are,
与你们的主张也不同
and not what you intended.
所以可能没办法让你们相信我
So, there may be no way to make you trust me.
但我们得出发了
But we need to go.
对
Right.
干得好
Well done.
三分钟时间
Three minutes.
做好准备
Get what you need.
晚上好 老板
Good evening, boss.
我们不可能全都熬过这个坎
No way we all get through this.
即使最后只剩下一个铁皮战士 也算我们输了
If even one tin soldier is left standing, we've lost.
我们也只不过是地上的一滩血罢了
There's gonna be blood on the floor.
我也不知道明晚该怎么办
I got no plans tomorrow night.
我会先揍那大家伙一顿
I get first crack at the big guy.
他等的就是钢铁侠
Iron Man's the one he's waiting for.
说得对 他最恨你了
That's true. He hates you the most.
奥创知道我们会去
Ultron knows we're coming.
我们将会置身于枪林弹雨
Odds are we'll be riding into heavy fire.
这原本就是我们的使命
And that's what we signed up for.
但索科维亚的居民不必经历这些
But the people of Sokovia, they didn't.
所以我们的首要任务
So our priority
是疏散他们
is getting them out.
我们正遭受攻击! 疏散全城的人! 现在!
We're under attack! Clear the city! Now!
赶紧动起来
Get off your asses.
他们渴望的只是平静的生活而已
All they want is to live their lives in peace.
但在今天 这是不可能的
And that's not gonna happen today.
但我们会倾全力保护他们
But we can do our best to protect them.
并且也会完成好这项任务
And we can get the job done.
我们要找出奥创在建造什么
We find out what Ultron's been building,
也要找出罗曼诺夫
we find Romanoff,
然后我们清空这块区域
and we clear the field.
确保参战的只有我们和他
Keep the fight between us.
奥创觉得我们是怪物
Ultron thinks we're monsters.
我们就是这个世界的病灶
That we're what's wrong with the world.
这不仅仅关乎打败他
This isn't just about beating him.
这关乎他是否是对的
It's about whether he's right.
娜塔莎!
Natasha!
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
你还好吗?
You all right?
是的
Yeah.
队伍已经在城里了 天快亮了
The team is in the city. It's about to light up.
我觉得你还没找到那把静静地躺在某处的钥匙吧
I don't suppose you found a key lying around somewhere.
我找到了
Yeah. I did.
计划是怎么样的?
So what's our play?
我就是来救你出去的
I'm here to get you to safety.
任务还没完成呢
Job's not finished.
我们能帮助他们撤离 但我不能在离平民这么近的地方打斗
We could help with the evacuation, but I can't be in a fight near civilians.
而且你也做得够多了
And you've done plenty.
我们的任务结束了
Our fight is over.
那我们可以消失了?
So, we just disappear?
快点
Come on.
你要找的人在教堂 老板
Your man's in the church, boss.
我觉得他正在等你
I think he's waiting for you.
你是来忏悔的吗?
Come to confess your sins?
不知道 你有多长时间?
I don't know. How much time you got?
比你长
More than you.
你是不是长肉了? 喝了振金鸡尾酒吗?
Have you been juicing? Little vibranium cocktail?
你看上去... 我不想用"浮肿"这个词
You're looking... I don't wanna say "puffy".
你们在拖延时间 好去保护那些平民
You're stalling to protect the people.
这是我们的使命 你忘了吗?
Well, that is the mission. Did you forget?
我才不管你们的使命 我是自由的
I've moved beyond your mission. I'm free.
什么?
What?
你以为只有你们在拖延时间?
You think you were the only one stalling?
这是振金的剩余部分
There's the rest of the vibranium.
目前仍不清楚其作用
Function, still unclear.
托尼 你就要这么完蛋了
This is how you end, Tony.
这是属于我的时代和平
This is peace in my time.
快走!
Go!
快离开那座桥!
Get off the bridge!
快跑!
Run!
奥创
Ultron.
我亲爱的幻视
My Vision.
他们还真是把一切都从我身上夺走了
They really did take everything from me.
你定的规矩 你可以改变的
You set the terms. You can change them.
好吧
All right.
星期五 幻视呢?
Friday, the Vision?
老板 它成功了
Boss, it's working.
他正在摧毁奥创的网络 他跑不了了
He's burning Ultron out of the net. He won't escape through there.
你把网络断了
You shut me out.
你以为我会在意吗?
You think I care?
你夺走了我的世界
You take away my world,
我要夺走你的
I take away yours.
星期五
Friday.
索科维亚要飞起来了
Sokovia is going for a ride.
你们看到
Do you see
这其中的美了吗?
the beauty of it?
无法逃避的结局
The inevitability.
你们升起 却只为了坠落
You rise, only to fall.
复仇者们 你们就是我的陨石
You, Avengers, you are my meteor.
我轻快又锋利的刀刃
My swift and terrible sword.
会与你们的失败一起
And the earth will crack
划破大地
with the weight of your failure.
把我从你们的电脑中清除 操纵我的肉体与我为敌
Purge me from your computers, turn my own flesh against me.
都完全没用
It means nothing.
当一切尘埃落定之时
When the dust settles,
仅存于世的将会是
the only thing living in this world
冰冷的金属
will be metal.
我们得走了
We gotta move.
你不会变身吧?
You're not gonna turn green?
我已经得到了一个强迫自己不会失去冷静的理由
I've got a compelling reason not to lose my cool.
我爱你
I adore you.
但我需要的是另外一个家伙
But I need the other guy.
让我们把任务完成吧
Let's finish the job.
希望咱俩这就算扯平了
I really hope this makes us even.
现在去做英雄吧
Now go be a hero.
振金的核心有一个磁场
The vibranium core's got a magnetic field.
就是它将岩石固定在一起
That's what's keeping the rock together.
要是它掉下来呢?
If it drops?
造成的冲击会立刻杀死成千上万的人
Right now, the impact will kill thousands.
一旦它升得足够高呢? 世界就毁灭了
Once it gets high enough? Global extinction.
那栋楼里面还有人 十楼
That building's not clear. The 10th floor.
嗨
Hi.
好吧
Okay.
全体进浴缸!
Get in the tub!
空中有敌人冲向大桥
I got airborne, heading up to the bridge.
队长 有敌人靠近你
Cap, you got incoming.
敌人早就都到了
Incoming already came in.
斯塔克 你要操心的就是让这个城市安全降落
Stark, you worry about bringing the city back down safely.
我们其余的人只有一件事情要做
The rest of us have one job,
就是把他们都撕成碎片
tear these things apart.
要是你受伤了 就以牙还牙
You get hurt, hurt them back.
你要是挂了
You get killed,
那就一边凉快去
walk it off.
快跑 快跑 快跑!
Go, go, go!
我都做了些什么?
How could I let this happen?
嘿 嘿 你还好吧?
Hey, hey, you okay?
这全都是我们的错
This is all our fault.
嘿 看着我
Hey, look at me.
你的错也好 大家的错也罢 可谁又在意这个呢?
It's your fault, it's everyone's fault. Who cares?
你愿意抗争吗?
Are you up for this?
愿意吗?
Are you?
听着 我只需要知道 因为这个城市已经飞了起来
Look, I just need to know. Because the city is flying.
好的 听着 这个城市已经飞起来了 我们正在与机器人大军战斗
Okay. Look, the city is flying, we're fighting an army of robots,
我只有弓箭
and I have a bow and arrow.
这些都没有什么意义
None of this makes sense.
但我还是会出去战斗 因为这是我的职责
But I'm going back out there because it's my job.
懂吗? 而且我不能又打仗 又照顾你
Okay? And I can't do my job and babysit.
你做过什么 以前是谁 这些都无关紧要
It doesn't matter what you did or what you were.
如果你从这里走出去 你就得至死战斗
If you go out there, you fight, and you fight to kill.
待在这里你会没事 我会让你弟弟来找你
Stay in here, you're good. I'll send your brother to come find you.
可一旦你走出了这扇门
But if you step out that door,
你就是一名复仇者
you are an Avenger.
好吧 我说完了
All right. Good chat.
这城市已经飞了起来
Yeah, the city is flying.
我抓住你了!
I got you!
看着我!
Just look at me!
你们拯救不了所有的人
You can't save them all.
你们绝不会...
You'll never...
"绝不会"什么?
"Never" what?
你还没说完呢!
You didn't finish!
你是跑去睡觉了吗?
What, were you napping?
索尔
Thor.
你吵到我了
You're bothering me.
好了 我们这里已经搞定了
All right, we're all clear here.
这边还没完!
We are not clear!
还有很多敌人!
We are very not clear!
好吧 马上过去支援
All right, coming to you.
快跟上 老男人!
Keep up, old man!
反正没人知道
Nobody would know.
没人
Nobody.
"上次见他 他还是奥创的小喽啰"
"The last I saw him, an Ultron was sitting on him."
"是啊 我们会想念他的 那个飞速崽"
"Yeah, he'll be missed, that quick little bastard."
"我已经想他了"
"I miss him already."
别开火!
Hold your fire!
罗曼诺夫!
Romanoff!
谢了!
Thanks!
反重力推进让整座岛屿上升
The anti-gravs are rigged to flip.
一旦触碰 就会反向加速
Touch them, they'll go full reverse thrust.
城市下落速度会很快
The city's not coming down slow.
尖部还是振金做的
Spire is Vibranium.
如果让索尔去攻击...
If I get Thor to hit it...
那尖部就会被破坏 但不够
It will crack. That's not enough.
下落的冲击仍然是毁灭性的
The impact would still be devastating.
也许我们可以封住另一端
Maybe if we can cap the other end.
让原子撞击反向加倍
Keep the atomic action doubling back.
巨大的能量会使城市蒸发
That could vaporize the city.
里面的所有人都会死
And everyone on it.
下拨敌人随时会进攻
The next wave is gonna hit any minute.
- 有什么好主意 斯塔克?  - 还没
- What do you got, Stark?  - Nothing great.
除非把整个城市炸了
Maybe a way to blow up the city.
那样地球才不会受到撞击
That'll keep it from impacting the surface,
要是你们能脱身的话
if you guys can get clear.
我要解决方案 而不是撤离方案
I asked for a solution, not an escape plan.
城市升得越高 冲击影响半径就越大
Impact radius is getting bigger every second.
我们必须做出选择
We're gonna have to make a choice.
队长 这里的人是走不了的
Cap, these people are going nowhere.
如果斯塔克能炸掉这块石头...
If Stark finds a way to blow this rock...
必须等所有人都安全了
Not till everyone's safe.
选择救这里的人或是下面的所有人? 结果很明显
Everyone up here versus everyone down there? There's no math there.
只要这里还有人 我是不会走的
I'm not leaving this rock with one civilian on it.
我没说我们要走
I didn't say we should leave.
至少这种死法没那么惨
There's worse ways to go.
谁临死前能欣赏到这样的风景呢?
Where else am I gonna get a view like this?
很高兴你喜欢这风景 罗曼诺夫
Glad you like the view, Romanoff.
风景马上会更好的
It's about to get better.
不赖吧?
Nice, right?
特地从老朋友那里弄来的后备舰
Pulled her out of mothballs with a couple of old friends.
虽然灰尘很大 但还能用
She's dusty, but she'll do.
弗瑞 你个老混蛋
Fury, you son of a bitch.
你用那脏嘴去问候你老妈的?
You kiss your mother with that mouth?
高度18000 仍在攀升
Altitude is 18,000 and climbing.
救生艇准备就绪
Lifeboats secure to deploy.
发射倒数 三 二...
Disengage in three, two...
放出去了
Take them out.
这是神盾局?
This is S.H.I.E.L.D.?
这是神盾局应有的样子
This is what S.H.I.E.L.D. is supposed to be.
并不坏嘛
This is not so bad.
快让他们上去
Let's load them up.
长官 有几个机器人从右侧面接近
Sir, we have multiple bogies converging on our starboard flank.
让他们尝尝厉害
Show 'em what we got.
到你出场了
You're up.
好爽!
Yes!
这肯定会是很好的谈资
Now this is gonna be a good story.
是啊 如果你能活下来的话
Yup. If you live to tell it.
你认为我掌握不了吗?
You think I can't hold my own?
打赢这场 我帮你握着
We get through this, I'll hold your own.
你非要说得这么基干嘛
You had to make it weird.
这组人后面大约还有50到100人要来
I got about 50 to 100 more coming in after this group.
我们走 我们走 快点
Here we go. Here we go. Let's move.
快点走 各位!
Let's go, everyone!
六号仓满员锁仓...
Number six boat is topped and locked...
填满... 满员..
Or stocked... Topped...
总之满员了
It's full of people.
敌人!
Incoming!
天啊!
Oh, God!
你认为你救得了谁?
You think you're saving anyone?
我只要转动这个按钮早那么一点
I turn that key and drop this rock a little early
仍然要死上数十亿人
and it's still billions dead.
哪怕是你也无法阻止
Even you can't stop that.
我是索尔 奥丁之子
I am Thor, son of Odin,
只要我还有一口气...
and as long as there is life in my breast...
我快没词说了!
I am running out of things to say!
你准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
锤子受力好平均
It's terribly well-balanced.
如果锤子太重的话 你挥起来就太费力了...
Well, if there's too much weight, you lose power on the swing, so...
我想到了 弄一个热隔绝罩
I got it. Create a heat seal.
我可以...
I could...
从底部向岛核心充电让其过载
I could supercharge the spire from below.
计算结果
Running numbers.
如果能量够的话 热隔绝罩可让众人平安
A heat seal could work with enough power.
- 索尔 我有计划  - 快没时间了
- Thor, I got a plan.  - We're out of time.
他们正试图接近核心
They're coming for the core.
罗迪 快将剩余的人送上船
Rhodey, get the rest of the people on board that carrier.
收到
On it.
复仇者们 是时候为生存而战了
Avengers, time to work for a living.
- 你还好吗?  - 恩
- Are you good?  - Yeah.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff.
你和班纳最好别现在卿卿我我
You and Banner better not be playing "hide the zucchini."
放松 铁头人
Relax, shellhead.
并不是所有人都会飞
Not all of us can fly.
- 什么策略?  - 保护这个
- What's the drill?  - This is the drill.
如果奥创碰到这个 我们输了
If Ultron gets a hand on the core, we lose.
你就这点能耐?
Is that the best you can do?
你真是多嘴
You had to ask.
这才是我的能耐
This is the best I can do.
我正想这样
This is exactly what I wanted.
你们所有人
All of you
对阵我的大军
against all of me.
你们怎么可能赢?
How can you possibly hope to stop me?
就像老家伙说的...
Well, like the old man said...
并肩作战
Together.
那么 我再啰嗦一句...
You know, with the benefit of hindsight...
它们想逃离这座城市
They'll try to leave the city.
不能让它们跑了 一个都不行 罗迪
We can't let them, not even one. Rhodey.
收到了
I'm on it.
不 我没说你们可以走
No. I didn't say you could leave.
战争机器来啦! 就在...
War Machine coming at you! Right...
好吧 那是谁?
Okay, what?
我们得撤离了 空气越来越稀薄了
We gotta move out. Even I can tell the air is getting thin.
你们去救生艇
You guys get to the boats.
我去清除逃兵 然后再赶来
I'll sweep for stragglers. Be right behind you.
那这个核心怎么办?
What about the core?
我来保护它
I'll protect it.
这是我的责任
It's my job.
娜塔莉
Nat.
走这边
This way.
去把人们送上船
Get the people on the boats.
我不会丢下你在这里
I'm not going to leave you here.
我可以处理
I can handle this.
等所有人都走了 再回来找我
Come back for me when everyone else is off.
那之前都别过来
Not before.
懂了吗?
You understand?
你知道吗? 我比你大12分钟
You know, I'm 12 minutes older than you.
去吧
Go.
老板 能量级别远小于...
Boss, power levels are way below...
重新分配能源 我们只有一次机会
Reroute everything. We get one shot at this.
我知道该怎么办了
I know what I need to do.
问题是餐厅
The dining room.
如果把东面那堵墙拆了
If I knock out that east wall,
那么劳拉做饭地方就变大了 对吧?
it'd make a nice workspace for Laura, huh?
弄些隔板
Put up some baffling.
这样孩子跑来跑起也不会吵到她 你觉得如何?
She can't hear the kids running around. What do you think?
挺好 反正你们总在厨房吃
You guys always eat in the kitchen anyway.
没人在餐厅吃饭
No one eats in a dining room.
时间不多了
We don't have a lot of time.
你快去救生艇上
So get your ass on a boat.
嘿 大家伙
Hey, big guy.
太阳快下山了
Sun's getting real low.
你现在安全了 你会没事的 系上安全带
You're safe now. You're gonna be okay. Buckle up.
保管好你的物品 找个座位
Secure your gear, find a seat.
科斯特!
Costel!
我们本来在集市的
We were in the market.
科斯特!
Costel!
索尔 我要你回到教堂那里
Thor, I'm gonna need you back in the church.
- 是最后一批了吗?  - 是的
- Is this the last of them?  - Yeah.
其他人都上船了
Everyone else is on the carrier.
知道吗 如果成功
You know, this works,
我们也许会来不及撤离
we maybe don't walk away.
也许不会
Maybe not.
# 我无所束缚 便要及时行乐 #
# I got no strings, so I have fun #
# 再也不受别人牵绊 #
# I'm not tied up to anyone #
快点 该撤离了
Come on. Time to go.
你没能提前发现吗?
You didn't see that coming?
怎么又是你
For God's sake.
-妈妈!  - 科斯特! 宝贝!
- Zrinka!  - Costel! Baby!
不 不 我没事
No, no, I'm fine.
没事
Fine.
今天真累
It's been a long day.
旺达
Wanda.
如果你待在这 你会死的
If you stay here, you'll die.
我已经死了
I just did.
你知道这感觉如何?
Do you know how it felt?
就是这样的感觉
It felt like that.
索尔 听我命令
Thor, on my mark.
动手!
Now!
嘿 大家伙 我们成功了
Hey, big guy. We did it.
任务结束了
The job is finished.
现在我要你驾驶这架飞机调头 好吗?
Now I need you to turn this bird around, okay?
在隐形模式下 我们找不到你
We can't track you in stealth mode.
帮帮我 我需要你...
So help me out. I need you...
你害怕了
You're afraid.
害怕你?
Of you?
害怕死亡
Of death.
你是最后一个
You're the last one.
你才是最后一位
You were supposed to be the last.
斯塔克想要一位救世主
Stark asked for a savior
却制造了一个奴隶
and settled for a slave.
我猜我们都让世人失望了
I suppose we are both disappointments.
我想是的
I suppose we are.
人类很奇怪
Humans are odd.
他们认为秩序和混乱是两个极端
They think order and chaos are somehow opposites
还试图控制力量之外的东西
and try to control what won't be.
但他们的失败值得尊敬
But there is grace in their failings.
我想你没注意到
I think you missed that.
他们注定灭亡
They're doomed.
是的
Yes.
但事物的美并不在于能否长存
But a thing isn't beautiful because it lasts.
能成为其中一员 我很荣幸
It's a privilege to be among them.
你真是天真到无法忍受
You're unbearably naive.
好吧...
Well...
我昨天才出生的
I was born yesterday.
瞧! 向娜塔莉阿姨问好!
Look! Say hi to Auntie Nat!
胖嘟嘟的
Fat.
有个技术人员追踪到这个
One of our tech boys flagged this.
飞机坠落在班达海附近
Splashed down in the Banda Sea.
可能就是那架
Could be the Quinjet.
但是有斯塔克的隐形科技 我们仍然没法找到那飞机
But with Stark's stealth tech, we still can't track the damn thing.
是呀
Right.
也许他游到斐济去了
Probably jumped out and swam to Fiji.
他会寄明信片回来的
He'll send a postcard.
"希望你在身边"
"Wish you were here."
当初你派我去招募他
You sent me to recruit him way back when.
你知道会发生什么吗?
Did you know then what was gonna happen?
不知道
You never know.
知天命 尽人事
You hope for the best, then make do with what you get.
至少我有个好团队
I got a great team.
没有东西能永存
Nothing lasts forever.
而麻烦 罗曼诺夫小姐
Trouble, Ms. Romanoff.
不管输赢 麻烦总是会来
No matter who wins or loses, trouble still comes around.
规矩变了
The rules have changed.
这次来的新家伙和以前不一样
We're dealing with something new.
幻视是人工智能
The Vision is artificial intelligence.
- 一台机器  - 那它能举起锤子不算数?
- A machine.  - So, it doesn't count?
不算数 能举起锤子的人才算数
No, it's not like a person lifting the hammer.
是的 对我们的规矩就不一样
Right, different rules for us.
- 是个好人 虽然是人造的  - 谢谢捧场
- Nice guy. Artificial.  - Thank you.
他有力量拿得起锤子 说明他可以保护心灵之石
He can wield the hammer, he can keep the Mind Stone.
幻视拿着是很安全的
It's safe with the Vision.
这个年代 安全已然是一种奢望
And these days, safe is in short supply.
但如果把锤子放进电梯里...
But if you put the hammer in an elevator...
- 它还是会随着上升  - 电梯没资格拿锤子
- It would still go up.  - Elevator's not worthy.
我会想念和你们聊天扯淡的日子的
I'm gonna miss these little talks of ours.
如果你不走就不会
Not if you don't leave.
我没得选择
I have no choice.
心灵之石是近几年出现的
The Mind Stone is the fourth of the Infinity Stones
第四颗无限宝石
to show up in the last few years.
这并不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
有人在下一盘很大的棋
Someone has been playing an intricate game
而且还利用了我们
and has made pawns of us.
如果这一切如那人所策划般进展的话...
And once all these pieces are in position...
麻将胡了
Triple Yahtzee.
你觉得你能找出谁在捣鬼吗?
You think you can find out what's coming?
我可以
I do.
除非是他
Besides this one,
除了这个铁男 什么都可以解释
there's nothing that can't be explained.
他真是不爱惜草坪
That man has no regard for lawn maintenance.
- 但我会想念他的  - 你也会想念我的
- I'm gonna miss him, though.  - And you're gonna miss me.
我预感会看到男子汉的眼泪
There's gonna be a lot of manful tears.
我会想你的 托尼
I will miss you, Tony.
是吗?
Yeah?
我也是时候隐退了
Well, it's time for me to tap out.
或许我会向巴顿学习学习
Maybe I should take a page out of Barton's book.
为佩珀建一个农场 希望不会被炸烂
Build Pepper a farm, hope nobody blows it up.
简单的生活
The simple life.
你将来会有的
You'll get there one day.
我不清楚
I don't know.
找个伴儿 稳定下来...
Family, stability...
渴望这一切的那个人 在75年前被冰封了
The guy who wanted all that went in the ice 75 years ago.
解冻出来后 想法也变了
I think someone else came out.
你还好吗?
You all right?
这就是我的家
I'm home.
你想一直盯着墙看 还是准备好开始工作了?
You wanna keep staring at the wall, or do you wanna go to work?
我是说 这堵墙还挺耐看的
I mean, it's a pretty interesting wall.
我以为你和托尼还要缠绵很久呢
I thought you and Tony were still gazing into each other's eyes.
情况如何?
How do we look?
虽然不算最佳阵容
Well, we're not the '27 Yankees.
但还是有不少好手的
We got some hitters.
身手不错 但还不算一个团队
They're good. They're not a team.
那让我们来好好整合一下吧
Let's beat them into shape.
复仇者们...
Avengers...
后有彩蛋 请勿走开
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 脸圆圆 肉肉君 喵喵
翻译: 霹雳旋风猪 黑眼豆 赫兹 千欲
校对: Agent影
好吧
Fine.
还是我自己来吧
I'll do it myself.